messed around he's nice
めちゃくちゃ彼はいいです
and
と
a
ある
Today we are inviting Professor Zhong Sunlin from the Department of Geological Sciences, National Taiwan University
本日は国立台湾大学地質科学部から鍾孫林教授をお招きします。
Then my child will introduce it
じゃあうちの子が紹介するよ
He was born in 1959 and is now 54 years old
彼は1959年生まれで現在54歳です。
I won't say anything about this girl
この女の子については何も言いません
Then he received his Ph.D. from the Department of Geology, National Taiwan University in 1990.
その後、1990 年に国立台湾大学地質学部で博士号を取得しました。
We sometimes emphasize now and sometimes
私たちは時には今を強調し、時には
The PhDs we train in Taiwan are also world-class.
私たちが台湾で養成している博士号取得者も世界クラスです。
He should be the same as our rebel headmaster Yang
彼は私たちの反逆的なヤン校長と同じでなければなりません
That's called MIT
それはMITと呼ばれます
Mate in Taiwan
台湾のメイト
PhD is from Taiwan
博士号は台湾出身
Then the Ph.D. that I got now continues to teach at National Taiwan University
その後、取得した博士号は現在も国立台湾大学で教鞭をとっています。
But from 1992 to 1993 to the University of Rennes in France
しかし、1992年から1993年までフランスのレンヌ大学に留学
postdoctoral research
博士研究員
This one who came to Australia in 7 years
7年ぶりにオーストラリアに来た人
Tasmania is an island south of Australia.
タスマニアはオーストラリアの南にある島です。
is an island twice the size of Taiwan
台湾の2倍の大きさの島です
there are universities
大学があります
that mineralogy is famous
その鉱物学は有名です
where they visit
彼らが訪れる場所
After returning to China, he has been teaching at National Taiwan University.
中国に帰国後は国立台湾大学で教鞭をとっている。
In 2001, our Central Plains Institute of Earth Sciences also
2001 年には、私たちのセントラル プレーンズ地球科学研究所も
Incarceration Fellows at the Institute
研究所の受刑者フェロー
His specialty is the dynamics of this geochemical
彼の専門はこの地球化学の力学です。
Phonics with Vulcan Circle
バルカンサークルを使ったフォニックス
Probably today's speech probably has something to do with this
おそらく今日のスピーチはこれと関係があると思われます
he took it three times
彼はそれを三回も受けた
three times at most
多くても3回
Three Distinguished Research Awards
3つの優れた研究賞を受賞
And this American Geological Society meeting
そしてこのアメリカ地質学会の会合では
Then Ministry of Education Academic Award
当時文部大臣学術賞受賞
Ministry of Education's National Award
国民文部大臣賞
Then Taiwan University Chaired Professor
その後台湾大学教授に就任
most importantly international
最も重要なことは国際的です
National Science Council's Public Collaboration Research Program
国立学術会議の公的共同研究プログラム
Our National Science Council's Public Collaboration Research Program
米国学術会議の公的共同研究プログラム
is to train Taiwan's academic leaders
台湾の学術指導者を育成することです
to the international level
国際レベルへ
His public policy is
彼の公共政策は
This name is similar to the name of this project
この名前はこのプロジェクトの名前に似ています
This is probably what he wants to introduce today
彼が今日紹介したいのはおそらくこれです
the name is called
名前が呼ばれます
His public project is called
彼の公共プロジェクトは次のように呼ばれています
Across Tibet to study Earth's in comparison
地球と比較して研究するためにチベットを横断
Three Generations Created by Two Collisions
二つの衝突が生んだ三世代
This is more strict
こちらの方が厳格です
or more academically
あるいはもっと学術的に
This is not an academic statement
これは学術的な声明ではありません
and crossed Tibet
そしてチベットを越えた
hug medical
ハグ医療
research error
研究ミス
this enjoys the scenery
これは景色を楽しんでいます
study geology
研究地質
our warm applause
私たちの温かい拍手
welcome is fair
歓迎は公正です
Is there a sound?
音はありますか？
have
もつ
Also share the introduction
紹介文もシェアします
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました
Everyone, I didn't expect so many people to come today
皆さん、今日はこんなにたくさんの人が来るとは思いませんでした
Teacher Peng said that I admire the teacher profession most in National Taiwan University
彭先生は、私は国立台湾大学の教師という職業を最も尊敬していると言いました
So he asked me to come and I couldn't refuse him
それで彼は私に来るように頼んだ、そして私は彼を断ることができなかった
Actually, I'm not very good at giving customer service speeches.
実は私、接客スピーチがあまり得意ではありません。
But since it's here, there's a story in the middle
でもここにいるからには途中に物語がある
Let me just say by the way that you Xu made today's opening remarks
ところで、徐さんは今日の冒頭の挨拶をしましたね。
The contact for this speech was actually at the beginning of October last year
実はこの講演の連絡があったのは昨年の10月初旬でした。
Vice President Peng's secretary will contact me
彭副総統の秘書が私に連絡します
I just want him to contact me and say to contact me in early October
10月初旬に彼から連絡が欲しいです
Then he said that he would make a speech at the end of October.
そして、10月末にスピーチをすると言いました。
I just say
私はちょうど言います
Oops, is that because the person in front didn’t tell me to call me?
ああ、前の人が電話しろって言わなかったからですか？
But because Mr. Peng wanted it
しかし、彭氏がそれを望んでいたため、
So I dare not refuse
だからあえて断らない
I said ok then I'll come
分かった、じゃあ行きますって言った
That
それか
When I made an appointment, I found out that he was actually talking about this year.
アポイントを取ってみると、実は今年のことを話していたことが分かりました。
Contact in October last year will come this year
去年の10月の連絡が今年も来る
So I waited in line for a year to get here to speak
それで私はここで講演するために1年間列に並びました
So you have to wait in line first
なので、まず列に並んで待たなければなりません
Actually, I should be going at this time
本当はこの時間に行くべきだった
We're having that 125th annual meeting in Denver right now.
私たちは今、デンバーで第 125 回年次総会を開催しています。
That special section with an Iranian address in it
イランの住所が含まれる特別なセクション
The host originally asked me to give a talk
主催者はもともと私に講演を依頼しました
But I said I had scheduled a speech a year ago
でも私は1年前にスピーチを予定していたと言いました
so i can't go to that
だからそこには行けない
I just have to come to this
ここまで来るしかない
what i want to talk about today
今日話したいこと
Because look at that time is two hours
その時間は2時間だから見てください
I don't know how long I'm going to talk
いつまで話すか分からない
But everyone line up
でもみんな並んでる
Then I also sneaked to the Internet to have a look
それから私もこっそりインターネットにアクセスして調べてみました
Approximately how much time did the previous speaker spend
前のスピーカーが費やした時間はおよそどれくらいですか
So of course I lined up 78 slides
もちろん、78枚のスライドを並べました
78 slides in one
78 枚のスライドを 1 つにまとめたもの
If each one speaks for one minute on average
一人が平均して 1 分間話すとすると、
I can speak for about 80 minutes
80分くらい話せます
So I hope there is still some time to take your questions
それでは、まだご質問をお受けする時間があれば幸いです
But when I speak, I tend to speak faster and faster.
しかし、話すときはどんどん早く話す傾向があります。
The faster you speak, there are many things that may be unknown
もっと早く話してください、知らないことがたくさんあるかもしれません
or something unclear
または不明瞭な何か
if you would like to listen a little more
もう少し聞きたいなら
You are welcome to interrupt me anytime
いつでも中断していただいて結構です
I don't need to raise my hand
手を上げる必要はない
just press your microphone
マイクを押すだけです
call while i'm out of breath
息が切れている間に電話して
I'm willing to stop anytime
いつでもやめるつもりです
Let me explain a little more to you
もう少し詳しく説明させてください
or usually both
または通常は両方
I heard they are very polite
とても礼儀正しいと聞きました
according to the last
最後によると
Bring it up when it's all said and done
すべてが終わったらそれを取り上げてください
bring it up for discussion
それを議論に持ち出す
that's also very welcome
それも大歓迎です
i want today
今日欲しいです
Just like Mr. Peng said just now
彭さんが今言ったように
I went to Tibet to go to Youshan with Wulang to play in the water
チベットに行って、ウーランと一緒にヨウ山に行って水遊びをしました
Playing in the oil mountains and playing in the water is actually pretty good
油の山で遊んだり、水で遊んだりするのは実際にはかなり良いです
This is the study of geology
これは地質学の研究です
one of the few advantages
数少ない利点の 1 つ
I shouldn't have said that
そんなこと言うべきじゃなかった
one of the advantages
利点の1つ
that I have been doing for many years
私が何年もやっていること
One of the studies on this
これに関する研究の一つに、
I'm here to tell you today
今日はそれを伝えるためにここに来ました
The story of the so-called geological road project
いわゆる地質道路プロジェクトの話
at the beginning
初めに
use my old slide first
最初に古いスライドを使用してください
because of copyright issues
著作権の問題があるため
That idea was planned from
そのアイデアはから企画されました
this gentleman is here
この紳士はここにいます
he is wal
彼はウォールです
He formed the so-called Music Project
彼はいわゆるミュージックプロジェクトを結成した
Because of this server project
このサーバープロジェクトのせいで
They have a certain Vision
彼らは特定のビジョンを持っています
we think we can borrow
借りられると思います
It's all about effects
すべてはエフェクトです
For this server project
このサーバー プロジェクトの場合
For example they
たとえば彼らは、
I hope this can create a new form of music
新しい音楽の形が生まれることを願っています
so that he may feel he can escape
そうすれば彼は逃げられると感じるかもしれない
The family of classical music
クラシック音楽一家
or related category
または関連するカテゴリ
We want to come here to study this idea
私たちはこのアイデアを研究するためにここに来たいです
do some geology research
地質学の研究をする
Hope to make some new observations
新たな観察ができることを期待しています
Then finally the so-called
そして最後に、いわゆる
Noisy Mountain Collision Theory
騒々しい山の衝突理論
some new insights
いくつかの新しい洞察
Even new ideas come
新しいアイデアも生まれます
This is the Vision of our Stuff Effect
これがスタッフエフェクトのビジョンです
This thing actually happened in the past two or three years
実はここ2、3年でこんな事があった
To unlock a private project that may be the smallest for Taiwan compatriots
台湾同胞にとっておそらく最小かもしれないプライベートプロジェクトのロックを解除するために
This private project is the private plan of Yongbao in 2011 by our long-term insurance expert Lin Yujie
このプライベート プロジェクトは、2011 年に当社の長期保険専門家、リン ユジエが永宝のプライベート プランとして作成したものです。
They spent years preparing
彼らは何年もかけて準備した
spent three months on mobile
移動に3ヶ月を費やした
From Istanbul, Turkey
トルコ・イスタンブール出身
Then run east all the way to Lanzhou in mainland China and end
その後、中国本土の蘭州まで東に走り、終了します。
A total of three months in the mainland within three months
3か月以内に本土で合計3か月
as long as you play tv in Chinese
中国語でテレビを再生している限り
Often see related reports
関連レポートをよく見る
They prepared for years and spent three months running him
彼らは何年もかけて準備し、3か月をかけて彼を動かしました
Our private program has been in existence for 17 or 18 years.
私たちのプライベート プログラムは 17 ～ 18 年前から存在しています。
run from Taiwan
台湾から逃げる
First ran to Southeast Asia and then gradually ran to Tibet
最初は東南アジアに走り、その後徐々にチベットに走りました
Finally started in the past six or seven years
ここ6、7年でようやく始まりました
Further west into Iran into the elevated lock into Türkiye
さらに西にイランに入り、トゥルキエの高架水門に入る
The final destination so far is to go to Istanbul
今のところ最終目的地はイスタンブールです
I am the opposite of everyone
私はみんなとは正反対です
16, 17, 18 years
16、17、18年的時間
Or add my previous study schedule
または、以前の学習スケジュールを追加します
The preparation process is actually
実はその準備過程は、
I've been running this my whole life
私はこれを生涯ずっと実行してきました
run this ultra run
このウルトラランを実行してください
Haven't run yet
まだ終わっていない
Might as well run for a few years in the week until I
私が死ぬまで、週に数年間走ってもいいかもしれません
you can pick me
私を選んでいいよ
Finally in line for a year or two
ついに1、2年並んだ
Maybe there is still a chance to come and think about it with everyone
もしかしたら、まだ皆さんと一緒に考えてみる機会があるかもしれません
Then I want to introduce this thing
そこで今回はこんなものを紹介したいと思います
start with this
これから始めます
I heard someone say
誰かが言うのを聞いた
The so-called Great Minds are discussing ideas
いわゆる偉大な頭脳がアイデアについて議論している
Average MindsDiscussion events
Average Mindsディスカッション イベント
As an old man, ask first
老人としてまず聞いてください
Of course everyone doesn't like it
もちろんみんなは嫌がるけど
He is Great Minds
彼はグレートマインドです
So he is discussing ideas
それで彼はアイデアについて話し合っています
but when he was young
しかし彼が若かった頃
when he was young
彼が若かったとき
Small minds discuss people when I was young
私が若かった頃、小さな心は人々について議論しました
So if start with
それで始めるなら
join this program
このプログラムに参加する
or me
それともわたし
People who do some cooperation started to introduce
何か協力してくれる人たちが紹介し始めた
because it's a
それは
The study that spanned many countries
多くの国にまたがる研究
many different collaborators
多くの異なる協力者
Then the middle is just the main collaborator
その場合、真ん中は主な協力者にすぎません
When including the Western Himalayas, partners from mainland China are required
西ヒマラヤを含める場合は、中国本土のパートナーが必要です
When doing Southeast Asia, Vietnam, Myanmar, India, and Malaysia are needed
東南アジアをやるならベトナム、ミャンマー、インド、マレーシアが必要
There are also some collaborators who are mixed with European and American people
協力者の中には欧米人と混ざった人もいる
when doing iran caucasus or turkey
イランのコーカサスやトルコをするとき
The same also needs to have some major local collaborators
これには地元の主要な協力者も必要です
opposite of name filing
氏名申告の反対
Of course, there is also the fellow who went to participate in Taiwan together
もちろん一緒に台湾に参加しに行った仲間もいます
Including several people from the Institute of Earth Sciences
中央研究院地球科学研究所の数名を含む
teachers and other colleges
教師と他の大学
Including teachers from Normal University and Chung Cheng University
師範大学と中正大学の教員を含む
Finally, of course, my colleagues at National Taiwan University
最後に、もちろん、国立台湾大学の同僚たちです。
But the most important behind-the-scenes engineering
しかし、最も重要な舞台裏のエンジニアリングは、
Because there is no way to write a list of names here
ここに名前のリストを書く方法はないので
The main load is less complex than the backup load
メイン ロードはバックアップ ロードよりも複雑ではありません。
Follow me if the main load is too heavy
メイン負荷が重い場合はフォローしてください
Graduate students who have worked with me over the past ten years
過去10年間一緒に働いてくれた大学院生たち
PhD Fellow or Research Assistant
PhDフェローまたはリサーチアシスタント
In fact, they played a very important role in the middle
実際、彼らは中盤で非常に重要な役割を果たしました
So I took the opportunity of today's speech by the way
さて、今日のスピーチの機会を利用して、
A big thank you to these anonymous behind-the-scenes staff
匿名の舞台裏で働く人々に多大な感謝を
Before I introduce it, I may want to talk about the background of geology.
それを紹介する前に、地質学の背景についてお話ししたいと思います。
Geological background we actually do research
実際に調査を行っている地質学的背景
are the major mountain ranges on earth to study
研究対象となる地球上の主要な山脈です
or major noise movement
または大きな騒音の動き
The main noise movements on Earth can be divided into two broad categories
地球上の主な騒音の動きは、大きく 2 つのカテゴリに分類できます。
A class called Eccretionary
Eccretionaryと呼ばれるクラス
Originate
起源
aerated noise band or noise movement
エアレーションされたノイズ帯域またはノイズの動き
The typical representative is Mount Annis in South America
代表的なのは南米のアニス山です
Or the words that were secretly played by the north in the past
あるいは過去に北が密かに奏でた言葉
The Heat Engine Mountains in North America are actually similar noise belts
北米のヒートエンジン山脈も実は同様のノイズベルトです
Their main mechanism is
それらの主なメカニズムは、
Party Ocean's ocean plate facing east screen
パーティーオーシャンのオーシャンプレート東向きスクリーン
Continental plates to North or South America
北アメリカまたは南アメリカへの大陸プレート
This is what is traditionally mentioned in the Plate Tectonics Society.
これはプレートテクトニクス協会で伝統的に言及されていることです。
screen effect
画面効果
Continental translation is called complementarity
大陸間の翻訳は相補性と呼ばれます
Over the past ten years, we have worked with our classmates in mainland China
過去 10 年間、私たちは中国本土のクラスメートと協力してきました。
Many people cooperate a lot, and now many Chinese translations have become translations of Communist bandits.
多くの人々が大いに協力し、今では多くの中国語翻訳が共産主義盗賊の翻訳になっています
I often forget what the translation for Taiwan is
台湾の訳をよく忘れてしまいます
In addition to the Occretionary Allusion type
付加暗示タイプに加えて
In addition, there is a very important shape type called Colitional Allusion
さらに、Colitional Allusion と呼ばれる非常に重要な形状タイプがあります。
In Chinese, it is called collision modeling.
中国語では衝突モデリングと呼ばれます。
A typical representative is the area to be introduced today
代表的なのが今回ご紹介するエリアです
In fact, starting from Tibet in the Himalayas in the east and going west
実際、東はヒマラヤのチベットから始まり西に向かっています。
Passing through Parnell into Iran
パーネルを通過してイランへ
Then go west into the Caucasus Mountains
その後、西に向かってコーカサス山脈に入ります
Inventory can be pushed all the way west to the Alps
在庫は西のアルプスまで押し出すことができます
Or the four mountains on the border between France and Spain
あるいはフランスとスペインの国境にある4つの山
They represent land masses from the south
それらは南からの陸塊を表します
The modeling movement caused by the collision with the original Eurasian continent in the north
北方の元のユーラシア大陸との衝突によって引き起こされた造形運動
This shape is geologically related to my noun
この形は地質学的に私の名詞と関連しています
called Pethean Allogenic Belts
ペテアン同種ベルトと呼ばれる
Chinese called Pethean Allogenic Belts
中国ではペテアン同種ベルトと呼ばれる
There used to be an ancient ocean called the Tethys Ocean.
かつてテチス海と呼ばれる古代の海がありました。
I'll take a little time to introduce it later
後ほど少し時間をおいてご紹介させていただきます
so to discuss this
だからこれについて話し合ってください
it is related to earth science or geology
それは地球科学または地質学に関連しています
over the past thirty to forty years
過去30年から40年にわたって
The most important theory is called plate
最も重要な理論はプレートと呼ばれます
or one of the most important theories
または最も重要な理論の 1 つ
The theory of plate tectonics is related to the proposal of the English name Playtronics
プレートテクトニクス理論は、プレイトロニクスという英語名の提案に関連しています
A doctrine or theory so far
これまでの教義または理論
still in geology
まだ地質学の研究中
Or geosciences which play a certain important opinion
あるいは、ある重要な意見を担う地球科学
I take this opportunity to introduce two famous people
この機会に二人の有名人を紹介します
When they were in the early 1970s
彼らが1970年代初頭にいた頃
This is the theory of plate tectonics
これがプレートテクトニクスの理論です
when it was first proposed
最初に提案されたとき
Started research into the so-called collision between India and the Asian continent
インドとアジア大陸とのいわゆる衝突に関する研究を開始
Like this is from an article they published in Science in 1975
これは 1975 年にサイエンス誌に掲載された記事からのものです
the first to call the shots
最初に決定権を握る人
Ugly caller now looks
醜い発信者の見た目
but that is
しかしそれは
The work result of the most Pioneer
最も先駆者の仕事の成果
Both gentlemen were at Masney College at the time.
両氏は当時マスニー大学に在学していた。
Is a young scholar at MIT
MITの若い学者です
Peter Mona was the assistant professor at that time
ピーター・モナは当時助教授だった
Then Paul Taponeer was a postdoc from France
当時、ポール・タポニアはフランスからのポスドクでした。
The two of them started a career at MIT
二人はMITでキャリアをスタートさせた
Then from this in India colliding with Eurasia in Tibet
そしてこれからインドでチベットでユーラシアと衝突します
A simterm was proposed in the study of Himalaya
ヒマラヤの研究でシミュレーションが提案されました
called continental tectonics
大陸テクトニクスと呼ばれる
They think continental tectonics and plate tectonics
彼らは大陸テクトニクスとプレートテクトニクスを考えています
are two completely different keys
2 つのまったく異なるキーです
It turns out that the plate that student or plate tectonics
プレートテクトニクスが原因であることが判明
It's the one from the oceanic plate
それは海洋プレートからのものです
The theory developed in the study in the ocean
海洋研究で開発された理論
And they go on top of the continental plates
そして大陸プレートの上に乗ります
Or it is said in the actual propaganda research in the mainland
あるいは本土の実際のプロパガンダ研究でも言われている
This study finds that it is not the same as in the ocean
この研究では、それが海洋と同じではないことが判明しました
So they have to make certain corrections
したがって、特定の修正を加える必要があります
For example, continental plates can produce
たとえば、大陸プレートは
It will produce deformation, contraction and expansion, and dragon fairy
変形、収縮、膨張を生み出し、ドラゴンフェアリーを生み出します。
that's why we have such big mountains, the himalals
それが私たちにこれほど大きな山、ヒマラールがある理由です
Then there is such a big plateau behind, Jinzang Plateau Longqi
そして後ろにはこんな大きな高原があり、金蔵高原龍旗です。
So this whole becomes the infinite situation of today's world
したがって、この全体が今日の世界の無限の状況になります
Then over the past ten years of research here
そして過去10年間にわたる研究がここで行われました
In particular, the continental crust here
特にここの大陸地殻は、
or the entire continental lithosphere, continental plates
または大陸リソスフェア全体、大陸プレート
Will it cause severe deformation?
ひどい変形を起こしてしまいますか？
with oceanic plates, or the traditional Play Deconics concept
海洋プレート、または伝統的な Play Deconics コンセプトを使用
is completely different, so they think
全く違うので彼らはこう思う
There is a new bucket face that needs to be studied in more detail
より詳細に研究する必要がある新しいバケット表面があります
Then the next thing I will do later will be related to the French relationship behind this
次に私が後で行うことは、この背後にあるフランスとの関係に関連することになります。
We have many, many wonderful entanglements with him now
私たちは今、彼とたくさんの素晴らしい絡みをしています。
Then if you watch Play Deconics
次に、Play Deconics を視聴すると、
this is one, could be one
これは 1 つです、1 つかもしれません
New Models of America, Play Deconics, Play Boundaries
アメリカの新しいモデル、デコニクスをプレイ、境界線をプレイ
There are about 50 large and small plates on the surface of the earth
地球の表面には大小50枚ほどのプレートが存在します
do mutual exercise each other squeeze each other
お互いに運動し合い、お互いに締め合います
呃呃interaction
呃呃interaction
then we will introduce
それではご紹介します
It's the little piece in the picture.
写真にある小さな部品です。
all
全て
Well
良い
my thinking plan
私の思考計画
if you
もし、あんたが
If you don't recognize this place
この場所が分からない場合
In fact, this place is mainly two
実はこの場所は主に2つあります
Well
良い
Continental to Continental Collision
大陸間の衝突
the one created by the orogen
造山運動によって作られたもの
uh mountains
ああ、山
is currently on Earth
現在地球上にいます
most important
最重要
or the most
またはほとんど
uh uh
ああ、ああ
conspicuous two colliding wars
顕著な二つの衝突戦争
one is here
1人がここにいます
yes this is tibet
はい、ここはチベットです
Or with the mountains around Tibet
あるいはチベット周辺の山々
linked together
一緒にリンクされた
To the north is Space Mountain.
北にはスペースマウンテンがあります。
There is also Carat Space, to the south is the Himalayas
カラットスペースもあります、南にはヒマラヤ山脈
etc.
等
together this
一緒にこれ
I call it the Tibetan Himalayan War for short.
私はこれを略してチベット・ヒマラヤ戦争と呼んでいます。
it is mainly
それは主にです
This section should be ruled
この板を支配すべきだ
reciprocal motion to the north
北への往復運動
Hitting the Eurasian road plate
ユーラシアの道路プレートに衝突
The result of this place
この場所の結果
What about its west side?
その西側はどうでしょうか？
There's another Collision War zone
もう一つの衝突紛争地帯がある
it is the arabic plate
それはアラビアプレートです
I bought most of them in Asia, and this place was made
ほとんどはアジアで購入しましたが、ここは作られました
These two states, if we use a little bit
この 2 つの状態を少し使ってみると、
It is a map projected from major earthquakes
大地震から投影された地図です
Or if the earthquake takes it away
あるいは地震がそれを奪ってしまったら
You can see that this color can actually come out
実際にこの色が出てくるのが分かります
These two are to the east or west of Asia
この二つはアジアの東か西にあります
I call it the East Asian collision zone for short.
私はそれを略して東アジア衝突地帯と呼んでいます。
Collision with Western Asia Brings Humans
西アジアとの衝突が人類をもたらす
The most obvious difference is that this one is fatter
最も明らかな違いは、こちらの方が太いことです
this is thinner
これは薄いです
same principle
同じ原理
I used to be slim
昔はスリムだったのに
But now it has become more and more like Mr. Peng
でも今はますます彭氏に似てきました
I'm physically
私は物理的に
so
それで
This compares
これは比較します
Compare
比較
Immense
計り知れない
then this
それからこれ
this
これ
narrow
狭い
The time with which this crime took place
この犯罪が起こった時間
There are relationships
関係性はあります
We call this collision zone a relatively mature collision zone.
このコリジョン ゾーンを比較的成熟したコリジョン ゾーンと呼びます。
because it started earlier
先に始まったので
In geological history, probably
地質史的にはおそらく
60 million years
6000万年
That is, around 60 million years ago
つまり約6000万年前
India and Asia collide
インドとアジアが衝突
This collision zone is a younger collision zone
このコリジョン ゾーンは新しいコリジョン ゾーンです
it happened earlier
それは以前に起こりました
This time may be about 30 million years in the average concensus
この時間は平均的なコンセンサスでは約 3,000 万年である可能性があります
It started only about 30 million years ago
それはわずか約3000万年前に始まりました
So half younger than this
つまりこれより半分若い
so this young
それでこの若い
And at the same time, it has a lot to do with the speed and intensity of the picture drama that collides with the plate
そして同時に、皿にぶつかるピクチャードラマのスピードと激しさも大きく関係しています。
Hardness runs fast
硬さは速く進みます
arabian run very slow
アラビア人はゆっくり走る
So if we look at this simple cartoon
この単純な漫画を見ると
The one who loves to learn will
学ぶことが好きな人は、
Diton Wheeler is made by Germans
ディトンウィーラーはドイツ人が作った
The digital picture drawn by the education plate reconstruction
教育プレート復元で​​描いたデジタル絵
but I simply treat it as
しかし私は単にそれを次のように扱います
You can see that the original hardness lags behind
本来の硬さが遅れているのがわかります
Then anytime progress hardness ran to the front
そうしたらいつでも硬さが先に走った
So hard like an Indian cheetah
インドのチーターみたいに硬い
the animal that runs as fast as a tough cheetah
タフなチーターと同じくらい速く走る動物
Then the Arabic plate
続いてアラビアプレート
In fact, they are all glued to this huge flying boat plate.
実際、それらはすべてこの巨大な飛行艇のプレートに接着されています。
So the airship is like a bubbun
だから飛行船はバブンみたいなものだ
It is lined up from the Southern Continent Pioneer
南大陸の開拓者からラインナップ
but it runs very slowly
しかし、それは非常にゆっくりと実行されます
move slowly north
ゆっくりと北へ進む
India's departure time is relatively late
インドの出発時間は比較的遅いです
But it's last come first come fast
でも、早い者勝ちですよ
Run to the north and south and then first load to the edge of Eurasia
北と南に走って、まずユーラシアの端までロードします
So here we build mountains first
ここでまず山を作ります
On the contrary, the mountain formation was late
逆に山の形成が遅れた
It's more intense here
ここはもっと激しいです
because india runs fast
インドは走るのが速いから
So here's the orogenic India
ここが造山地帯のインドです
You're doing more than what's being done here
ここで行われていること以上のことを行っています
right
右
This is the case of General
これは将軍の場合です
If you push back the history of the earth
地球の歴史を遡れば
longer words
長い言葉
It's just the schematic diagram of that and that.
あれやこれやの模式図です。
This is India is Africa
ここはインドだ、アフリカだ
Then India quickly ran up
するとインドがすぐに駆け寄ってきた
Africa is connected to the Arabian
アフリカはアラビアとつながっている
run slowly
ゆっくり走る
But this is in the history of the address
しかし、これはアドレスの履歴にあります
One hundred and twenty ninety million years
1億2900万年
Then if you push forward
それで前に進むと
one hundred and seventy million years
一億七千万年
two hundred and forty million years
二億四千万年
three hundred million years three hundred and forty
三百百萬年三百四十
Until five hundred and forty centuries
540世紀まで
Five hundred and forty centuries
540世紀
Probably the beginning of the cold afternoon season in address history
おそらくアドレスの歴史における寒い午後の季節の始まり
That is the beginning of the fifth generation
それが五代目の始まりです
The words before there are
その前の言葉は、
Is it the pre-cold noon season?
寒くなる前の昼の季節でしょうか？
nice to fly
飛んでよかった
in a different history
違う歴史の中で
You can see that the combination of the plates will change
プレートの組み合わせが変わるのがわかります
there will be one after another
次から次へとあるだろう
We specially put this picture about 24 million years old for you to see
約2,400万年前のこの写真を皆さんにご覧いただくために特別に掲載しました。
The topic I'm going to cover today is about
今日取り上げるテーマは次のとおりです
At this time there was a big ancient ocean
この頃、古代の大きな海がありました
This ancient marine geologist gave him a special name called the Tethys Ocean
この古代の海洋地質学者は彼にテチス海と呼ばれる特別な名前を付けました
English called Tesla Ocean
英文叫Tesla Ocean
Chinese translation
中国語翻訳
Ogain is the translation of the big country called Tethys
オーゲインはテティスという大きな国の翻訳です
Taiwan's translation is called ancient Mediterranean
台湾の翻訳は古代地中海と呼ばれています
if you have heard
聞いたことがあるなら
But Tethys is actually a very bad translation
しかし、テティスは実際には非常に悪い翻訳です
because it sounds hard
難しく聞こえるから
But Tethysthetis was actually a water god
しかし、テテュステティスは実際には水の神でした
Or Poseidon is a goddess of female beauty
あるいはポセイドンは女性の美の女神です
Translating Tethys can't show it at all
テティスを翻訳しても全く表示されない
So I secretly translated it into Daixis last time
なので前回こっそりダイクシスに翻訳してみました
That sounds like the name of a goddess
女神の名前みたいですね
At this time, the combination of Tethys Yang looks like this
この時のテティス・ヤンの組み合わせはこんな感じ
Tethys ocean geologists go further
テチスの海洋地質学者はさらに前進する
It can be divided into what is called Pilotastic called ancient
古代と呼ばれるPilotasticと呼ばれるものに分けられます
Mesotasis is called Mesotasis
メソタシスはメソタシスと呼ばれます
Called New Tedis sheep with Neotasis
ネオタシスを伴うニュー・テディス羊と呼ばれる
So there's a lot of subtle changes in between
したがって、その間には多くの微妙な変更があります
Then wait until the Paleozoic to Mesozoic period of this Earth's history
そして、この地球の歴史から古生代から中生代まで待ちます
Until the end of the whole evolution of the new generation
新世代の進化が終わるまで
Continents from the south make relative applications to the north
南からの大陸は北に相対的に適用されます
Finally close up this teddy sheep
最後にこの羊のぬいぐるみをクローズアップします
we get what we see today
私たちは今日見たものを手に入れます
The so-called error status band
いわゆるエラーステータスバンド
From Tibet, Himalayas, Europa to
チベット、ヒマラヤ、ヨーロッパから
Albert in the west, the Perakins, etc.
西のアルバート、ペラキンスなど。
Proper nouns in cartography
地図製作における固有名詞
In fact, it should be called Tephanogene belt
実際、それはテファノジェネベルトと呼ばれるべきです
It's the Teddis War Belt I mentioned earlier.
先ほど紹介したテディスウォーベルトです。
It is about taking this ancient Mediterranean
それはこの古代の地中海を手に入れることです
or after this teddy sheep is closed
またはこの羊のぬいぐるみが閉まった後
continental plates from the south
南からの大陸プレート
To the north is mainly the Eurasian continental plate
北には主にユーラシア大陸プレートがあります
when the main things come together
主要なものが集まったとき
the result of
結果
So my Chinese Academy of Sciences in Beijing
それで、北京にある私の中国科学院
Wu Furen
呉福仁
It's called they are also working on a joint project
共同プロジェクトにも取り組んでいるとのこと
The name of their joint project will be
彼らの共同プロジェクトの名前は
It's officially called the Tres project
正式には Tres プロジェクトと呼ばれます
everybody knows
誰もが知っている
The president's committee and geologists all know
大統領委員会も地質学者も皆知っている
But because my project is in Taiwan
でも、私のプロジェクトは台湾にあるので、
Then interdisciplinary students have to follow physical chemistry
その場合、学際的な学生は物理化学に従わなければなりません
Mathematics students compete together
数学の学生が一緒に競い合います
So it is necessary to take a comparison
だから比較する必要がある
Compare
比較
relatively unpronounceable name
比較的発音しにくい名前
So it becomes a four-way plan
つまり4方向の計画になります
The Tres plan is a very complicated thing.
トレス計画は非常に複雑なものだ。
i don't say it in particular
特に言いません
but must stand
でも立たなければならない
Also very important in geology
地質学でも非常に重要
The effect of the global global factor
グローバルグローバルファクターの影響
global impact
世界的な影響
not just on the road
道路上だけではなく
You can easily understand on the road
道中でもすぐに理解できる
because the board will hit
板が当たるから
then there are mountains formed
それから山が形成されます
So the authenticity on the watch is different
したがって、時計の真正性は異なります
when there is such a big plateau
こんなに大きな高原があると
when it melts
溶けたとき
Obviously the road will be affected
明らかに道路に影響が出ます
But the impact isn't just on the road
しかし、影響は道路上だけではありません
while in the sea
海の中にいる間
with the air
空気と一緒に
Air is the change in the atmosphere
空気とは大気の変化のこと
There are also very
とても
have a serious impact
深刻な影響を与える
like in terms of the ocean
海のことのように
Because of the movement of India to Arabia and North
インドのアラビアと北方への移動のため
Then the ancient Mediterranean will be specially closed
その後、古代地中海は特別に閉鎖されます
It turns out that the currents of the Atlantic Ocean and the Indian Ocean South
大西洋とインド洋の南の流れが変わっていることが判明
The currents of the Pacific Ocean are interconnected
太平洋の流れはつながっている
Wait until this channel is closed
このチャンネルが閉じられるまで待ちます
Wait until Arabia would have crashed into Eurasia
アラビアがユーラシアに衝突するまで待ってください
This channel is closed
このチャンネルは閉鎖されました
After closing, you can easily think of
閉店後に簡単に考えられるのは、
Global ocean currents are greatly affected and will change
地球規模の海流は大きな影響を受け、変化する
So this closing time
ということで今回の閉店時間は
Probably in the history of the earth
おそらく地球の歴史の中で
The 30 million years I mentioned earlier
先ほど話した3000万年
about 30 million years
約3000万年
30 million years in the history of the earth
地球の歴史3000万年
Oligocene is called gradually new type
漸新世は徐々に新しいタイプと呼ばれます
So when oscillating
したがって、振動するとき
In the evolution of earth history
地球の歴史の進化の中で
The event with a global cooling
地球規模の寒冷化を伴うイベント
As far as many scholars have begun to discuss
多くの学者が議論を始めている限りでは
Is it because of this change in ocean currents?
この海流の変化のせいでしょうか？
or the closure of this pipe
あるいはこのパイプの閉鎖
Is there any connection with the global goblin cooling?
世界的なゴブリンの寒冷化と何か関係があるのでしょうか？
Many related research associations
多数の関連研究団体
If changes to the global climate
地球規模の気候が変化したら
This is the impact on the air
これが空気への影響です
Effects are not limited to changes on land or on the ground
影響は陸上や地上の変化に限定されません
In fact, in the ocean
実は海の中で
or atmospheric wind twist
または大気の風のねじれ
will have a serious impact
深刻な影響を与えるだろう
in these fields
これらの分野で
Many related scholars are doing relevant research
多くの関連学者が関連研究を行っています
Then I will post a few more slides to talk about it
それから、それについて話すためにさらにいくつかのスライドを投稿します
what is my beijing friend
私の北京の友達は何ですか
no woman ready slide
無婦人準備的slide
So it's all simplified characters
なので全部簡体字です
So what is a special editor?
では、特殊エディタとは何でしょうか?
The special editor simply said that the earth
特別編集者は、地球はこう言っただけです。
There was an ancient ocean in between
中間存在過一個古海洋
ancient ocean
古代の海
we call
私たちは電話します
not us
私たちではありません
This is the first person to call him
この人が彼に初めて電話をかけた人です
is a supplementary student in Austria
オーストリアの補習生です
Named Tessis in 1893 called Swiss
1893年にスイスと呼ばれるテシスと名付けられた
Tessis is the beautiful lady
テシスは美しい女性です
Or he is Seafood Oceanus
それともシーフード・オシアナスなのか
So it should be translated into a more feminine name
だから、もっと女性的な名前に翻訳されるべきです
maybe less obtrusive
あまり目立たないかもしれない
So this is the Curtis Ocean in Earth's past history
つまり、これは地球の過去の歴史におけるカーチス海です
The southern hemisphere is not between the southern continent and the northern continent
南半球は南大陸と北大陸の間にはありません
an ancient ocean that once existed
かつて存在した太古の海
In the middle because this ancient ocean is now extinct
真ん中にあるのは、この太古の海はもう絶滅しているからです
So do not keep records that are no longer kept
したがって、保存されなくなった記録は保存しないでください
or a record kept in the address history
またはアドレス履歴に保存されている記録
are incomplete
不完全です
So there are many, many different arguments or different scholars
ですから、非常に多くの異なる議論や異なる学者がいます。
offer different explanations
さまざまな説明を提供する
Like one of the scholars who wrote an article
論文を書いた学者の一人のように
Specifically to take advantage of the difference in the spelling of Curtis's name
特にカーティスの名前のスペルの違いを利用するため
In fact, there are many, many different debates in it
実際、そこには非常に多くの異なる議論があります
How should Curtis be composed?
カーティスはどのように構成すべきでしょうか？
Then the time of his formation
それから彼の結成の時期
where does he exist
彼はどこにいますか
How did he evolve
では彼はどのように進化したのか
have many different interpretations
さまざまな解釈がある
Or even more naughty is a Turkish geoscientist named Chera Sengo
または、さらにいたずらなのは、チェラ・センゴという名前のトルコの地球科学者です。
His dedicated article discusses
彼の特別な記事では、
Teddy's story
テディの物語
Then Punchline is
じゃあパンチラインは
How many wives did oceanists have?
海洋学者には何人の妻がいましたか?
How many wives do oceanists have?
海洋学者には何人の妻がいますか?
If you want to know a little more about Teddy Yang's story
テディ・ヤンの物語についてもう少し詳しく知りたい場合は
i always recommend
私はいつもお勧めします
my student
私の生徒
but you are not my students
でもあなたたちは私の生徒ではありません
then i will talk about shanko
それからシャンコについて話します
Say a lot to use that wiki site
その Wiki サイトを使用するために多くのことを言ってください
Wikipedia actually has a lot of related information
ウィキペディアには実際に関連情報がたくさんあります
So you just hit Testis Ocean
つまり、Testis Ocean に到達するだけです
You can find a lot of related information on Wikipedia
ウィキペディアで関連情報がたくさん見つかります
Then I'll make this Teddys case tape.
それからこのテディのケースのテープを作ります。
or do this idea
またはこのアイデアを実行してください
There are so many complex geological problems
非常に多くの複雑な地質学的問題がある
of course do everything
もちろん全部やります
Then my reasoning for that research
では、その研究に対する私の理由は、
Like the introduction of Punchline just now
さっきのパンチラインの紹介みたいに
Geochemistry of mainly igneous rocks
主に火成岩の地球化学
So holding hands to two is
だから二人で手を繋ぐのは
The first is geochemical
一つ目は地球化学です
Geochemistry means
地球化学の意味
We use chemical knowledge or technology to study
化学の知識や技術を使って勉強します
Earth Today or Study Earth's History
今日の地球、または地球の歴史を学ぶ
So using chemical
そこで化学薬品を使うと
Our Tongren Association Academia Sinica at National Taiwan University
私たちの同仁協会 国立台湾大学中央研究院
There are many sessions dedicated to geophysics
地球物理学に特化したセッションが多数あります
They use their knowledge of physics
彼らは物理学の知識を活用します
or physical techniques to study the earth
または地球を研究するための物理的テクニック
eventually modern earth science is hope
やがて現代の地球科学は希望となる
All the knowledge and technology at our disposal
あらゆる知識と技術を自由に活用できます
Come to study and do modern earth science research
現代の地球科学の研究と研究に来てください
So we claim to be modern geoscientists
つまり私たちは現代の地球科学者であると主張します
I thought the former students were sitting in the back when I said that
私がそう言ったとき、元生徒たちが後ろに座っていたのかと思いました。
Or my students don't quite believe
それとも生徒たちがあまり信じていないのか
i am a modern earth
私は現代の地球です
chemist or modern geoscientist
化学者または現代の地球科学者
Because I still don't know how to use a mobile phone
携帯電話の使い方がまだ分からないので、
because it's geochemistry
地球化学だから
The other one is igneous rock
もう一つは火成岩です
Fire dust rock means
火の粉石の意味
molten rock uses rocks formed in volcanoes or magma
溶岩は火山やマグマで形成された岩石を使用します
This is my research session
これは私の研究セッションです
so in this area
だからこの地域では
In the history of Alu Collision Stitching
アルミコリジョンステッチの歴史の中で
lots of magmatism
多くのマグマ活動
Many rock records of igneous rocks have been left
火成岩の岩石記録が数多く残されている
So we're here to study
だから私たちは勉強するためにここにいます
This magmatism
このマグマ活動は
leave a record and then study his chronology
記録を残してから彼の年表を調べてください
when was it formed
いつ結成されましたか
study his origins
彼の起源を研究する
What are his primitive characteristics?
彼の原始的な特徴は何ですか？
what kind of stone is it made of
どのような石でできていますか
and then study the composition of his geochemistry
そして彼の地球化学の組成を研究します
and then combine these
そしてこれらを組み合わせます
What about the records of Yanjiang's homework?
延江さんの宿題の記録はどうなっているのでしょうか？
he will tell us something
彼は私たちに何かを教えてくれるでしょう
this
これ
collision history or creation
衝突履歴または衝突の作成
some records in the process
処理中のいくつかのレコード
Then this kind of research needs a basic assumption
この種の研究には基本的な前提が必要です
The assumption is that
仮定は次のとおりです
There is a certain relationship between the research and Xinjiang activities and the so-called plate tectonic work
この研究と新疆の活動およびいわゆるプレートテクトニクス活動との間には一定の関係がある。
When the plate tectonic environment changes
プレートテクトニクス環境が変化するとき
Yanjiang
延江市
If it is produced to research the ingredients of Xinjiang
新疆の成分を研究するために生産された場合
or his primordial character
あるいは彼の根源的な性格
will follow
フォローします
Under different plate tectonic environments before
以前の異なるプレートテクトニクス環境下では
The composition of a Yanjiang produced is different
延江産の成分が違う
for example
例えば
The research frontier formed before the collision between India and Asia
インドとアジアの衝突前に形成された研究フロンティア
India and Asia
インドとアジア
Yanjiang formed after the collision
衝突後に延江が形成された
it will have a very different documented nature
文書化された性質が大きく異なります
We just need to know when he made this change
彼がいつこの変更を加えたのかを知る必要があるだけです
he'll tell us
彼は私たちに教えてくれるでしょう
how did this collision happen
この衝突はどのようにして起こったのか
what happened in this process
この過程で何が起こったのか
we look fun
私たちは楽しそうだ
Wait a minute and I'll give you a few examples
ちょっと待ってください。いくつか例を示します
such a hypothesis
そのような仮説
We have done a lot of work in Tibet
私たちはチベットで多くの仕事をしてきました
Tibet is from an article I published in 2015
チベットは 2015 年に公開した記事から
The first graph, the first extreme simplification
最初のグラフ、最初の極端な単純化
Address map of Tibet
チベットの住所地図
I tell you this is the time to oversimplify
今は単純化しすぎる時期だと言います
Everyone smiled incomprehensibly
みんな意味不明な笑みを浮かべた
or some kind of smile
あるいはある種の笑顔
But this is indeed an extremely simplified address map
しかし、これは実際には非常に単純化されたアドレス マップです。
I can explain to you well because of this time
こんな時期だからこそしっかり説明できます
Divide the whole Tibet into one, two, three, four, five, six
チベット全体を1、2、3、4、5、6に分ける
Seven kinds of stones are posted on this picture
この写真には7種類の石が掲載されています
you really have a chance to see
本当に見るチャンスがあります
The address on the Tibetan Plateau
チベット高原での演説
Densely packed with dozens of rocks of different ages
さまざまな年代の数十の岩が密集しています
or stratum
または地層
Twice very very tutoring
2回の非常に非常に個別指導
This is an extremely simplified spectrum
これは非常に単純化されたスペクトルです
Then use such an extremely simplified synthesis
次に、このような非常に単純化された合成を使用します。
We can then discuss what the tectonic evolution of the Tibetan Plateau looks like
その後、チベット高原の地殻変動がどのようなものであるかを議論することができます。
If you are interested, please take a look
興味のある方はぜひご覧ください
But it is not suitable for me to talk too much about that old stuff
でも、そんな古いことについてあまり話すのは私にはふさわしくない
But this article is quite resonant
しかし、この記事はかなり反響があります
We spent a lot of time doing this
私たちはこれに多くの時間を費やしました
Published in a geological neutralization period called erscience review
erscience review と呼ばれる地質学的中性化期間に出版
science review has a statistic in 2010
サイエンスレビューには2010年の統計があります
We got a good citation for this article
この記事について良い引用をいただきました
It is the paper defined by the ranking in all the highly cited papers
すべての高被引用論文の中でのランキングによって定義される論文です
So it's still useful to draw some effort
したがって、少し努力することはまだ役に立ちます
Then do something like this
それから次のようなことをしてください
As I said just now, my research is called
先ほども言いましたが、私の研究は
modern digital art learning English is really modern
現代のデジタルアート英語学習は本当に現代的です
That is closely related to the development of that instrument and technology.
それはその機器や技術の発展と密接に関係しています。
Let me briefly talk about some kind of technical chemical development
ある種の技術的な化学開発について簡単に話させてください
with the technological development of so-called spectrometers
いわゆる分光計の技術開発により
Mass spectrometer is mass spectrometer
分光計は質量分析計です
Now we technical chemists use many kinds of spectrometers
現在、私たち技術化学者はさまざまな種類の分光計を使用しています
to do the measurement we want
必要な測定を行うには
That way that precise measurement
そうすれば正確な測定ができます
We call it prime number
私たちはそれを素数と呼びます
It is mass spectrometry
質量分析です
For example, the element we need
たとえば、必要な要素は
or isotopic measurement
または同位体測定
We just try to find a way in the periodic table
私たちは周期表に方法を見つけようとしているだけです
find our suitable element or isotope
適切な元素または同位体を見つける
Then use mass spectrometry to do accurate
次に、質量分析を使用して正確な分析を行います。
or that precise measurement at very low levels
または非常に低いレベルでの正確な測定
can achieve what we want
私たちが望むことを達成できる
The technological development of this kind is about the same as that of the past ten years
この種の技術開発はここ10年とほぼ同じです
To some extent, the Department of Geology at National Taiwan University is similar to the so-called
国立台湾大学の地質学部は、いわゆる地質学部にある程度似ています。
The knowledge plan of 50 billion in five years has a lot to do with it
5年間の500億知識計画が大きく関係している
So 50 billion in five years is actually
つまり、5年間で500億というのは実際には
Actually did a lot of good things
実際に良いことたくさんやったよ
at least in row
少なくとも一列に
We took this opportunity to set up a couple of really nice labs
私たちはこの機会を利用して、本当に素晴らしいラボをいくつか設立しました
In the past few years, I have made a lot of new observations and new bags
ここ数年、私はたくさんの新しい観察と新しいバッグを作りました
Including some research results in the thinking plan that I will introduce to you later
後ほどご紹介する思考プランに研究成果を盛り込みます
The front is all introduction
正面が全てのご紹介です
To see this, to talk about my thoughts and plans
これを見るため、自分の考えや計画について話すため
Since it is an imitation
模造品なので
Youyou Music Ideas Project
ユーユーミュージックアイデアプロジェクト
So I will divide it into about three components to introduce to you
ということで3つほどに分けてご紹介していきます
divided into preludes
プレリュードに分かれている
then enter the topic
それからトピックに入ります
then finally to the finale
そしていよいよフィナーレへ
The prelude will probably be divided into two parts
前奏曲はおそらく2部に分かれるでしょう
The topic will be divided into two parts
このトピックは 2 つの部分に分かれます
One is a good place in the Tibetan Himalayas in the east
一つは東のチベット・ヒマラヤの良い場所です
then one is tibet
じゃあ一つはチベット
To the west are the two regions from the Caucasus to Iran
西にはコーカサスからイランまでの 2 つの地域があります
It is related to a very strange research project in China.
それは中国の非常に奇妙な研究プロジェクトに関連しています。
This research project was developed by us 17 or 18 years ago
この研究プロジェクトは 17 ～ 18 年前に私たちが開発したものです
Starting to leave Taiwan and go to Southeast Asia to do geological science research
地質科学研究のため台湾を離れ東南アジアへ渡り始める
A topic I thought up with my feet in my head
頭に足を入れて考えたテーマ
So our research project is called CREATE
私たちの研究プロジェクトは CREATE と呼ばれています
Tainan Chinese is simply called the East Asian Terran Tectonic Research Integration Project
台南中国語は単に東アジア地殻研究統合プロジェクトと呼ばれます
English name is Comprehensive Research on East Asia Tectonic Evolution
英文叫Comprehensive Research on East Asia Tectonic Evolution
Become a Synchron name called CREATE
CREATEというシンクロン名になります
We hope this will convince the review committee of the State Council
これが国務院の審査委員会を納得させることを願っています
Give us a little more funding for research
研究にもう少し資金をください
We can go to places outside of Taiwan to work hard and see
私たちは台湾の外の場所に行って一生懸命働き、見ることができます
On the one hand, self-encouragement hopes that we can create some new observations or theories to
一方で、自己励ましは、私たちが何らかの新しい観察や理論を生み出すことができることを期待しています。
This research project is now part of the Ninth Science Division of Congress
この研究プロジェクトは現在、議会の第 9 科学部門の一部となっています。
It was a very successful plan
とても成功した計画でした
Because it has lasted for sixteen seventeen years and has not been terminated
それは1617年間続いてまだ終了していないからです
Seventeen years is about three years we have been together
17年というと、私たちが一緒に過ごして約3年になります
It is now in the sixth period
現在6期目に入っています
Three sixty-eight will have a total of eighteen years of planning
368人は合計18年間の計画を立てることになる
Now in middle second year of sixth period
現在6期中2年です
So now I'm doing the research project for the 17th year
現在、17年目の研究プロジェクトを行っています。
Hosley, we can still maintain a certain creativity
ホスリー、私たちはまだ一定の創造性を維持できます
Do a few more years of related work in the next few years
今後数年間でさらに数年間関連する作業を行う
What about the create research project?
研究プロジェクトの作成についてはどうですか?
The first place to start is in Southeast Asia
まずは東南アジアからスタート
Mount Ai Lao on the Red River in Vietnam
ベトナムの紅河にあるアイラオ山
In Vietnam part is actually the Red River
ベトナムの一部は実際には紅河です
If anyone has ever been to North Vietnam
北ベトナムに行ったことのある人がいたら
Going northwest from Hanoi
ハノイから北西へ
you will see a big river
大きな川が見えます
That river is the Red River
あの川は赤い川です
The Red River is actually a very big break
レッドリバーは実際には非常に大きなブレイクです
or fault zone
または断層帯
So the reason why I chose to start solving the problem here
ここで問題の解決を始めることにした理由
We were originally studying the formation of the South China Sea
私たちはもともと南シナ海の形成を研究していました
There is a theory about the formation of the South China Sea
南シナ海の形成についての理論がある
It has something to do with the activity of this big fault zone.
それはこの大きな断層帯の活動と関係があります。
Its range is about 1000 kilometers long
その射程距離は約1000キロメートル
is a big fault
それは大きな間違いです
lasted 1000 km
1000km続いた
So a fault about three times as long as Taiwan
つまり台湾の約3倍の長さの断層
so do it here
だからここでやれよ
It is completely different from the scale in Taiwan.
台湾とは規模が全然違います。
Why this big break
なぜこの大ブレイクなのか
Or why you want to do research on this large fault zone
あるいは、なぜこの大きな断層帯について研究したいのか
It's related to the job of the gentleman I mentioned earlier named Taboneer
それは先ほど話したタブネールという紳士の仕事に関係しています。
Taboneer with some colleagues or students at the University of Paris
パリ大学の同僚や学生たちとタブーナー
Started publishing successive research papers in 1986
1986年から次々と研究論文を発表し始める
Let's talk about this fault zone
この断層帯について話しましょう
The importance of this fault zone is
この断層帯の重要性は、
They think that after India collided with Asia
彼らはインドがアジアと衝突した後だと考えている
In addition to causing the hearing impairment
聴覚障害を引き起こすだけでなく、
The amphibious continental extortion caused by the dragon body on the Tibetan plateau in East Asia
東アジアのチベット高原の龍体によって引き起こされた水陸両用の大陸恐喝
Experiments of the mainland's descent or complementation
本土の降下または補完の実験
like pool
プールのような
You hit it and two balls go out
打つとボールが2つ出ます
Then two boards ran out
その後、ボードが2枚なくなりました
After sports hit
スポーツが流行った後
The southeast pottery that first formed the Southeast Asian plate
東南アジアの皿を最初に形成した南東部の陶器
Then cause the Tibetan plateau plus the relative motion of eastern Asia to the east
次に、チベット高原と東アジアの東への相対運動を引き起こします。
The boundary between the first period and the second period is the Red River Erosendian era
第一期と第二期の境目は紅河エロセンディアン時代
model is very famous
模型非常有名
Until now
今まで
in all geology
あらゆる地質学において
Textbooks of structural geology have this picture
構造地質学の教科書にはこんな写真が載っています
This is like a model of some kind
これは何かの模型みたいですね
or an authoritative explanation
または権威ある説明
Even because of this work and the NSF in mainland China
この作品と中国本土のNSFのせいでも
Their foundation committee declared that
彼らの財団委員会は次のように宣言しました。
The problems of this place have been solved by him
この場所の問題は彼によって解決されました
So any mainland China study
つまり、中国本土の研究では
Apply to study all of the research topics in this place
すべての研究テーマをここで学ぶために申し込む
kill them all
皆殺しにする
because there is no problem to do
やっても問題ないので
about 15 years ago
約15年前
When we set off in Taiwan to discuss
話し合いのために台湾に出発したとき
We thought this pattern was really beautiful
このモデルは本当に美しいと思いました
so beautiful let us think
とても美しいので考えてみましょう
that word is called
その言葉は呼ばれます
To be true
真であります
we just want to try it
私たちはただ試してみたいだけです
The national tiger who was not born with the poison of France
フランスの毒を持って生まれなかった国民の虎
I want to come here to challenge
ここに来て挑戦したい
have a look
見てください
Just choose this place to make our first step
最初の一歩としてこの場所を選んでください
Although there are certain risks
一定のリスクはあるものの、
feel like playing
遊びたい気分
may be more enjoyable
もっと楽しいかもしれない
When I went to Huashan, I met many
華山に行ったとき、たくさんの人に会いました
Study on the Ho Chi Minh Trail
ホーチミントレイルに関する研究
not so easy
そう簡単ではない
That's a small thing except the cable car
ケーブルカー以外は小さなことだ
but we
しかし、我々
good luck
幸運を
found in the previous 12 years
過去12年間に発見された
Several very important geological roads
いくつかの非常に重要な地質学的道路
then quickly do some
それから手早くやってください
analyze
分析
In 1997 and 1998 respectively in
1997年と1998年にそれぞれ
The mainstream period of the Georgia Society of America
アメリカジョージア協会の主流期
Called Georgia published two papers on the Red River Alasan fault zone
ジョージア州がレッド川アラサン断層帯に関する2つの論文を発表
That view is completely different from that of the French gang.
その見解はフランスのギャングの見解とはまったく異なります。
So there was an uproar
そこで騒動が起きた
From then on, the French hated the things that Tuantuan made very much.
それ以来、フランス人はトゥアントゥアンの作ったものを大嫌いでした。
The incomprehensible resources we have forged with him have continued to this day
私たちが彼とともに築き上げた理解できないリソースは今日まで続いています
I always tell people that this is an incomprehensible fate
私はいつも人々にこれは不可解な運命だと言います
Tarponia still hates our team so much
ターポニアは今でも私たちのチームをとても嫌っています
because some of the things we published
私たちが公開したもののいくつかは
I think there are many in the model that he was very beautiful at the time
当時はとても美人だったというモデルも多いと思います
The problem with Fundamental
ファンダメンタルズの問題
In fact, it should be the wrong foothold.
実際、それは間違った足場であるはずです。
So until now I'm still fighting
だから今に至るまで私はまだ戦っている
But for me personally, the research on the Red River Alashan fault zone is more important
しかし、私個人にとっては、レッド川アラサン断層帯の研究の方が重要です。
Track to the northwest by tracking the Red River Alashan
アラシャン紅河に沿って北西へ進む
This is where the Red River Alashan breaks
ここはアラシャン紅河が途切れる場所です
In the end we climbed up the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau
最後は青海チベット高原に登りました
So I went to the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau and made some things
それで私は青海チベット高原に行っていくつかのものを作りました
Also sent a paper that looks good
良さそうな紙も送っていただきました
But more importantly, after this prelude
しかし、もっと重要なのは、この前奏曲の後、
One of the topics we can remember to cover today
今日取り上げるべきトピックの 1 つ
It is the create project and Tibet research
クリエイトプロジェクトとチベット研究です
That went to the infinite of this world
そこは無限の世界
It's easy to think of words of encouragement
励ましの言葉を考えるのは簡単です
Quickly copy a sentence out
文章を素早くコピーアウトする
Everyone felt inspired and went to Tibet
誰もがインスピレーションを感じてチベットへ行きました
Up Zufan
アップ・ズファン
So I like to use this composite picture to say that so many people went
ですから、私はこの合成写真を使って、非常に多くの人が行ったということを言いたいと思います。
The people in the colorful photos are our working team
カラフルな写真の人々は私たちの作業チームです
Except this black and white
この白と黒を除いて
That's the other picture you saw on the poster
それはあなたがポスターで見たもう一つの写真です
This was when I was in Tibet about ten years ago
これは10年ほど前にチベットに行った時のことです
My graduate student at that time helped me take the photo
当時の大学院生が写真撮影を手伝ってくれました
Intentionally shot in black and white
意図的に白黒で撮影
It looks particularly memorable now
今では特に思い出深いようです
Looks like the one from Fuji
富士のものに似てる
The young man with a big bag on his back went to Tibet to learn Buddhist scriptures
大きな鞄を背負った青年は経典を学ぶためにチベットへ行った
explore that
それを探求する
is the secret of an address
住所の秘密です
When the boss was chatting
上司が雑談していたとき
He's 84 and it's been 10 years
彼は84歳で10年が経ちました
Now if he is still there
もし彼がまだそこにいるなら
hope he's still there
彼がまだそこにいるといいのですが
and in good
そして良い状態で
is 94 years old
94歳です
He looked very, very healthy at the time
当時彼はとてもとても健康そうに見えました
their next world
彼らの次の世界
this one
これです
It was only after the whole set was given to me that I found out
セット全体を渡されて初めて知りました
In fact, that Bradbitt has been working on that private road project for a long time.
実は、そのブラッドビットは長い間その私道プロジェクトに取り組んでいたのです。
run far ahead of me
私のはるか前を走​​る
Brad Beatt acted in a Hollywood movie when he was young
ブラッド・ビートは若い頃にハリウッド映画に出演していた
Called 7 Years in Tibet
チベットでの7年間と呼ばれる
Many people may have seen
見たことある人も多いかもしれない
It's about a late World War II
第二次世界大戦末期の話です
The story of an Austrian mountaineer named Hirish Barrow
ヒリッシュ・バロウという名前のオーストリアの登山家の物語
Last time I was stuck in my heart for 7 years
7年間心に引っかかっていた最後の時
And also met Dalai Nana
そしてダライ・ナナにも会いました
Dalai Nana's childhood story
ダライ・ナナの子供時代の話
If you haven't seen it, go and have a look
見てない方は行って見てください
Why do you say he is already working on a private road project?
なぜ彼はすでに私道プロジェクトに取り組んでいると言えるのですか？
You'll be fucking Brad Pitt later
後でブラッド・ピットとセックスすることになるよ
we didn't get a chance to see dallala
私たちはダララを見る機会がなかった
But we have seen many interesting geological phenomena in the plateau mountains
しかし、私たちは高原の山々で多くの興味深い地質学的現象を見てきました。
Also see a lot
こちらもたくさん見てね
A few photos I'm going to show you right now
今からいくつか写真をお見せします
distant hometown
遠い故郷
There are many Tibetan girls
チベット人の女の子がたくさんいる
There are also different costumes for people from different regions
地域によって服装も異なります
But they are all equally curious
しかし、彼らは皆同じ​​ように好奇心を持っています
There are Tibetan compatriots
チベット同胞がいる
then use this opportunity
それではこの機会をご利用ください
Thank you to the other two of our three cobblers
3 人の靴屋さんのうちの残りの 2 人に感謝します
We have been doing this create project from the very beginning until now
私たちはこのプロジェクトを最初から今まで続けてきました
One is my colleague Professor Luo Qinghua from National Taiwan University
一人は私の同僚である国立台湾大学の羅清華教授です。
The other is Professor Li Tongyi from STU
さらに、STUのLi Tongyi教授
They are on the plateau, they are suffering from this altitude sickness headache
彼らは高原にいて、高山病による頭痛に苦しんでいます。
Still willing to be my support until now
これからもずっとサポートしていきたいと思います
So take this time to show you
だからこの時間をかけてあなたに見せてください
The one from Game of three
ゲームオブスリーのもの
Then if you go to Tibet
それでチベットに行ったら
Working hours in Tibet are mainly in summer
チベットの労働時間は主に夏です
There is no way to work in winter
冬は仕事が出来ない
We can only enter the venue when we are in our appointment
約束の時間にのみ会場に入場できます
It's okay if you don't go out
外出しなくても大丈夫
Then I can't work again in July and August
そうなると7月と8月はまた働けなくなります
Because July and August is the rainy season
7月と8月は梅雨なので
You see, when it rains in Tibet, it is very troublesome
ほら、チベットに雨が降ると、とても困るんだよ
september october is a good time to work
9月10月は仕事をするのに良い時期です
then november
それから11月
it's going to snow in november
11月には雪が降ります
But even when working in the summer
でも、夏に仕事をしているときでも、
Still easy to see like this
こうやっても見やすいですね
look
見て
especially to northern Tibet
特にチベット北部へ
As long as there is a brook coming down, this is the virtue
小川が流れている限り、これが美徳だ
So high-level hospitals should not have been to Tibet
したがって、高レベルの病院はチベットに行くべきではなかった
otherwise
さもないと
August Snow may be able to write a little easier
8月 雪なら少しは書きやすくなるかも
The field is especially beautiful when it snows
雪の降る野原は特に美しい
like this one is tibetan steel thirteen
これはチベットスチールサーティーンのようなものです
Thirteen is a mountain range mainly composed of granite
十三山は主に花崗岩からなる山脈です
mountains of granite
花崗岩の山々
When it snows, we call it Yiyiyi
雪が降ると「イーイー」と呼びます
you can take pictures like this
このような写真を撮ることができます
But it's snowing and I still have to work
でも雪が降ったのでまだまだ仕事が必要です
Because there is not much time in a year to go
一年もあとあまり時間がないので
The advantage of being a teacher is that
教師であることの利点は、
You don't have to tell the students to go over by yourself
生徒たちに自分で行くように言う必要はありません
Then work hard during the semester
それでは一学期頑張ってください
young people are different
若者は違う
There are also high priority sheep in the blood particles
血液粒子には優先度の高い羊もいます
like this
このような
High atomic treasure is this guy
高い原子宝はこの男です
In short there are curious furry cows that touch near us
とにかく、私たちの近くに触れようとする好奇心旺盛な毛むくじゃらの牛がいます
Then their Zibao future products
その後、Zibao の将来の製品
Often used on the wall
壁によく使われます
This is the most successful photo I took on the letter
これは私が手紙で撮った中で最も成功した写真です
Just made a fool of myself
自分を馬鹿にしただけ
So it's not a question of camera skills
つまりカメラのスキルの問題ではない
It's a question of good scenery
良い景色の問題です
So it was used as a poster
ポスターとして使われたので
a big lake in the south of tibet
チベット南部にある大きな湖
Yang Zhuoyongcuo
ヤン・ジュオヨンクオ
very beautiful lake
とても美しい湖
So if you have the opportunity to go to Tibet
チベットに行く機会があれば
Don't forget to go to Yang Zhuo Yong wrong
間違って楊卓勇に行くのを忘れないように
But there will be altitude sickness
でも高山病になるよ
so you have to be mentally prepared
だから心の準備をしておく必要がある
But in fact, my body is fine.
でも実際、私の体は大丈夫です。
so you should be fine
だから大丈夫ですよ
that such a Tibet
そんなチベットとは
In fact, a serious problem was discovered immediately
実は重大な問題がすぐに発覚した
very serious problem is
非常に深刻な問題は
because this is the substance of the world
これが世界の実体だから
Research work since the 1990s or early 2000s
1990 年代または 2000 年代初頭以降の研究活動
After being hit easily
簡単に殴られた後
The problem of the highland dragon
高原龍生的問題
Or its Global Impact problem
あるいはその世界的影響問題
Therefore, the problems that everyone is doing are mainly on the initiative.
したがって、皆さんがやっておられる問題は主体的に取り組んでいる問題が中心でございます。
After India collided with Asia
インドがアジアと衝突した後
Problems with Tibetan plateau or whole size biomass
チベット高原またはホールサイズバイオマスの問題
How did the dragon come into being?
ドラゴンはどのようにして誕生したのでしょうか？
then how does it change
じゃあどう変わるのか
When you do your research you find out
研究してみると分かります
Each section is beautifully modeled
各セクションが美しくモデル化されています
all on a very loose pile of sand
すべては非常に緩い砂の山の上にあります
A very loose pile of sand is
非常に緩い砂の山は、
Boundary Conditions Before India's Collision With Asia
インドがアジアと衝突する前の境界条件
very very little data
非常にわずかなデータ
Everyone has done a very little information above
誰もが上記の情報をほとんど実行していません
Start developing its very nice model
非常に素晴らしいモデルの開発を開始
so we feel
だから私たちは感じます
Maybe someone should do a little guesswork
たぶん誰かが少し推測する必要がある
We chose this material to make
この素材を選んで作りました
The structure of the plate or extended circle before the collision
衝突前のプレートまたは延長円の構造
this matter
本件
That is, all collision models
つまり、すべての衝突モデル
In fact, the boundary conditions
実際、境界条件は
to study this thing
このことを勉強するために
This is the red stone
これが赤い石です
What we just said here is called steel bottom silk mountain
今ここで言ったのは、鋼底シルクマウンテンと呼ばれるものです。
Or we call it steel bottom wire rock mass
または、鋼底ワイヤー岩塊と呼びます。
or more broadly
またはもっと広く
I call this thing the Antis Mountain of South Asia
私はこれを南アジアのアンチの山と呼んでいます
How did Mount Antis of South Asia come about?
南アジアのアンティ山はどのようにして生まれたのでしょうか?
you just thought
あなたは今考えました
Antis Hill I just introduced
先ほど紹介したアンティスヒル
Enrichment-type impact scars
濃縮型衝撃瘢痕
Enlarged type of impact marks, right?
濃縮タイプの衝撃痕ですよね？
Is the Pacific plate like Dongying or Huchong
太平洋プレートは東営や湖浚のようなものですか
to the continental plate of South America
南アメリカの大陸プレートの下にある
out of the mountain
山から出た
That mountain is actually mainly
あの山は実は主に
As a human being, I will study the volcanic eruption itinerary of human beings
私は人間として、人類の火山噴火計画を研究します
if you have been to south america
南アメリカに行ったことがあるなら
you know the main mountain
あなたは主な山を知っています
Each one is a big volcano
それぞれが大きな火山です
same situation in this place
この場所でも同じ状況
If you pull that India out
インドを引き出せば
pull back
引き戻す
after pulling away
引き離した後
There is an ancient ocean that will come out
出てくる太古の海がある
That ocean is the Tethys Ocean I just mentioned.
その海は先ほど述べたテチス海です。
Tethys oceanic plate
テチス海洋プレート
So the oceanic plate is heading north
つまり海洋プレートは北に向かっている
Hidden sprawl went under the continental plate of South Asia
隠れたスプロールが南アジアの大陸プレートの下に潜り込んだ
so before the collision
だから衝突する前に
the one with the one that creeps northwards
北に向かって這うものと
Then built a rocky Andes on the edge of South Asia
その後、南アジアの端に岩だらけのアンデス山脈を築きました
Just before India collided
インド衝突直前
Here is a long-lived Saimai
長命のサイマイはこちら
like what we saw in the andes today
今日アンデスで見たもののように
But this South Asian Andes
しかし、この南アジアのアンデス
very low level of research
非常にレベルの低い研究
to its time to the process of its formation
その時代へその形成過程へ
what happened to the rock that caused it
原因となった岩はどうなったのか
There is only very, very little information
非常にわずかな情報しかありません
So when we went to Tibet in 2000
2000年にチベットに行ったとき
I decided to make some of this bitter dish
この苦い料理を作ることにしました
It starts from Gangdi Shishan here
ここはガンディ・シーシャンから始まります
I like to do Side with that quote from my friend
私は友人からのその言葉をサイドにするのが好きです
This is my good friend and my bad friend
これは私の良い友達であり、私の悪い友達です
because he always bothers me
彼はいつも私を困らせるから
That professor at Oxford University is called Mike Sear
オックスフォード大学のあの教授はマイク・シアーといいます
It's the great expert in the Himalayas
ヒマラヤの偉大な専門家
Working in the Himalayas for 30 years
ヒマラヤで30年間活動
is oxford university
オックスフォード大学です
He just posted it earlier this year
彼は今年初めにそれを投稿したばかりです
A science book called The Colliding Continents
『衝突する大陸』という科学本
don't come here often
頻繁にここに来ないでください
Go in and encourage you to buy a copy and take a look
入って、コピーを購入して見てみるように勧めてください
my name is mentioned in the middle
真ん中に私の名前が出ています
but i like racing a word in it
でも私はその中で言葉を競うのが好きです
i just said
私はちょうど言いました
In fact, one word is to say
実際、一言で言えば、
The first world is the fourth dimension
第一の世界は四次元です
The fourth dimension is time
四次元は時間です
is empty
空です
its a university study
それは大学の研究です
and most importantly
最も重要な
it understands everything in the world
それは世界のすべてを理解します
this is a saying
これは格言です
it can no longer be explained
それはもう説明できません
So when studying address evolution or address events
したがって、アドレス進化またはアドレスイベントを研究するときは、
very important thing
とても重要なこと
the past ten years
過去10年間
Luckily there is a new dating method
幸いなことに、新しいデート方法があります
It's not really new
それほど新しいものではありません
A dating method was developed by the meal
食事からデート法が開発された
There is a strange mineral in the time-lapse
タイムラプスには奇妙な鉱物があります
This mineral is abundant
このミネラルが豊富に含まれています
but useful
でも役に立つ
This mineral is called telling the truth
この鉱物は真実を語ると呼ばれています
English called Zircon
英語ではジルコンといいます
It's that one of those sour speeches
それはあの不機嫌なスピーチの一つです
Its chemical formula is VR-SIO4
化学式はVR-SIO4です。
So is the Zoccom Decidicates
Zoccom Decidicatesも同様です
That mineral is very tenacious
その鉱物はとても粘り強いです
it's after the bathroom
トイレの後です
it will grab a certain amount
一定の量を掴みます
then use it for a while to hold it will protect it
その後、しばらく使用して保持すると保護されます
don't let it go
放さないでください
Then use a very important placement element
次に、非常に重要な配置要素を使用します
Because it will go through Chanticare and finally become NProduct
Chanticareを経て最終的にNProductになるから
will become Chan
チャンになります
So with this placement system it's fine
だからこの配置システムなら大丈夫
Dating tool or make a nice Geo-Cronometer
年代測定ツールまたは素敵な地理クロノメーターを作成する
Then in addition to the age that the 6000 system can give
そして、6000系が与えることができる年齢に加えて、
tell the truth because it's tall
背が高いから本当のことを言う
So the other relative I sued is H
つまり、私が訴えたもう一人の親戚はHです
This element can be used for original measurement
この要素は独自の測定に使用できます
will make very accurate measurements
非常に正確な測定を行います
So that gives you the composition of the Ha isotope
これで Ha 同位体の組成がわかります
So this mineral can give you age at the same time
つまり、このミネラルは同時に老化をもたらす可能性があるのです
At the same time give you another isotope system
同時に別の同位体システムを提供します
Can be used as a so-called Isotropic Tracer
いわゆる等方性トレーサーとして使用可能
can tell you what the source that said it was made of
それが何からできていると言ったかの情報源を教えてください
So that over the past 10 years
つまり、過去10年間で
become an important one
大切なものになる
a fixed method
固定された方法
But why was it rarely used in the past?
しかし、なぜ過去にはほとんど使用されなかったのでしょうか?
mainly because it's small
主に小さいから
When each Boss grows in this master
このマスターで各ボスが成長すると
Often grow into such a thin and long look
多くの場合、このように細くて長い見た目に成長します
it will be around the waist
腰あたりになります
About 50 microns to 100 microns
約50ミクロン～100ミクロン
Micron is Uyghurni here
マイクロンはここのウイグルニです
10-6 anti-meter
10-6アンチメーター
So the right eye can't actually see
つまり右目は実際には見えない
To be seen under a highly magnified microscope
高倍率の顕微鏡で見ることができる
The length is usually one or two hundred micron
長さは通常 100 または 200 ミクロンです
Therefore, it was difficult to do precise measurement with the previous technology.
そのため、従来の技術では正確な測定を行うことが困難でした。
But because of laser technology
しかしレーザー技術のおかげで
is applied to this field of geochemistry
地球化学のこの分野に応用されています
very successful over the past ten years
過去10年間で大成功を収めた
So put the laser laser system
そこでレーザーレーザーシステムを設置します
Plus that jeep technology
さらにジープのテクノロジー
The technology we commonly use now is called laser ICBMS
現在私たちが一般的に使用している技術はレーザーICBMSと呼ばれています
You can do it very precisely in this small notice
この非常に小さな通知で非常に正確に実行できます
its right shoulder
その右肩
get its right shoulder parity
右肩の同等性を取得する
It is possible to calculate the age of its formation
形成年代を計算することが可能
can measure what's in it
中に何が入っているかを測定できる
The composition of Ha isodigits
Ha等桁の構成
This mineral now becomes
この鉱物は今、
very useful thing
とても便利なもの
Because our private program
私たちのプライベートプログラムなので、
A lot of factual analysis was done
多くの事実分析が行われました
The borrowed geologist changed a word
借りた地質学者は言葉を変えた
This is actually a word in Deville
これは実はデヴィルの言葉です
Deville is a temporary company
デビルは一時的な会社です
Temporary company's original advertisement called
という派遣会社のオリジナル広告。
Diamond is the best friend of women
ダイヤモンドは女性の親友です
So the geologists changed it to say
そこで地質学者はそれをこう変えました
Zerchrom is the best friend of geologists
ザークロムは地質学者の親友です
I give a practical example
実際的な例を挙げます
because my former student
私の元生徒だから
Dr. Meifei Zhu
朱美飛博士
sit there
あちらに座って
So it's his job to do a little bit with everyone
だから、みんなと一緒にちょっとしたことをするのが彼の仕事だよ
a little more introduction
もう少し紹介
Made by Zhu Meifei
朱美飛作
Inside the Primarch Gambis in the south of Tibet
チベット南部のPrimarch Gambisの内部
Score some tell the truth
スコアいくつかは真実を語ってください
This truth sometimes grows a little blunt
この真実は時々少し鈍くなることがあります
Some are slimmer
もっとスリムな人もいます
This is 50micron scale
これは50ミクロンスケールです
So this is about 100micron crown
これは約100ミクロンのクラウンです
This is about 6 or 70 micron crowns
これは約6または70ミクロンのクラウンです
In such a small truth
そんな小さな真実に
We can use laser ICPMS technology
レーザーICPMS技術を使用できます
It's in the contact with National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学と連携中です
our laboratory
私たちの研究室
This is a Laser System
これはレーザーシステムです
Behind this is a small ICM-MS
この後ろにあるのは小型の ICM-MS です
Spectrum of Inductive Couple and Plasma
誘導結合とプラズマのスペクトル
very long Chinese translation
とても長い中国語訳
put it together
一緒に置く
Small notices can be made with Laser
レーザーで小さな通知も可能
Laser Beam probably can
レーザービームならおそらくできる
Make a Micron
ミクロンを作る
Fraction typed out
Fraction打出来的
And send Kalor Gas to Zhipu
そしてカロルガスをジプーに送ってください
To analyze its right-shifted system Wei Subizi
右シフトシステムを分析するには 魏素碧子
To analyze its Hartung-Western Bizi
そのHartung-Western Biziを分析する
So like this ZQC Grant
このように ZQC 助成金
can play three holes
3ホールプレーできる
High time for three shots
3ショットのハイタイム
different ages available
さまざまな年齢層が利用可能です
and the different Ha Tung Wei Suzi
そして違うHa Tung Wei Suzi
this shot twice
このショットは2回
Its Core took a shot
そのコアが撃った
It's Room a shot
まさにルームです
get different ages
さまざまな年齢を得る
Obtaining a different metric ratio
異なるメトリック比率の取得
Finally, the result of our analysis is
最後に、分析の結果は次のとおりです。
XQC is from India
XQCはインド出身
The Room it grows from is local in Asia
それが育つ部屋はアジアのローカルです
It grows in the south of Tibet
チベットの南に生えています
So the implication is this telling
つまり、これが意味することは、
It was inside a stone
石の中にありました
it is from the indian plate
それはインドのプレートからです
Because India is warm and Asian wind is in Hong Kong
インドは暖かく、香港にはアジアの風が吹いているので
sent to the crust of the Asian continent
アジア大陸の地殻に送られる
Then in this tell the side length
次に、これで辺の長さを教えてください
one more ring
もう一つの指輪
It is the ring belt grown from the nutrients in Asia
アジアの栄養で育った環状帯です
So there is the Indian Core
インディアン・コアがあります
Then add Rhoome from the Asian continent
次に、アジア大陸からロームを追加します
grow like today
今日のように成長する
So the title of this final part is
というわけで、この最終回のタイトルは、
India's Hidden Input to Tibetan
インドのチベットへの隠された貢献
Originary Review by
元のレビュー:
Haffnima Stubbler
ハフニマ・スタブラー
Transit in my life in circumstance
私の人生におけるトランジットの状況
or Strax that middle detail
またはStraxその中間の詳細
I won't talk about it in particular
特に話さないけど
Such an application is actually
このようなアプリケーションは実際には
We can use such a small particle to tell
このような小さな粒子を使用して、次のことがわかります。
It's actually a micro scale thing
それは実際にはミクロスケールの事です
then after such a small
それからそのような小さな後
Analysis of the original flavor of the cross-thing
クロスシング本来の味わいの分析
we can discuss
話し合うことができます
Juguan Megascale
ジュグアンメガスケール
or the whole plot
またはプロット全体
Danish or Highland Evolution
デンマークまたはハイランドの進化
the one like this
このようなもの
Ban Guo Zao's question
Ban Guo Zao的問題
Therefore, the ancients said that the tool of health
したがって、古代人は健康の道具であると言った
We think there is actually a certain truth in it.
私たちはそこに確かな真実があると考えています。
We use such a technique
私たちはこのような技術を使用しています
Did it on Tibet for the past few years
ここ数年チベットでやってました
quite a bit of that work
その仕事のかなりの部分
An example of this is
この例としては、
eyeballs like this one or yellow eyeballs
このような目玉や黄色い目玉
or brown eyes
または茶色の目
It's what I just said
それは私が今言ったことです
the one from south asia
南アジアから来たもの
Dark Thirteen Above
ダークティーン・アバブ
the stone out of the ground
地面から出てきた石
So we go along this south side of Tibet
それで私たちはチベットのこの南側に沿って行きます
do the detailed one
詳しいことをする
no way to detail
詳細を説明する方法はありません
Do more detailed field work
より詳細な現場作業を行う
then sample
それからサンプル
Then tell the truth
それから真実を話してください
followed by petrology
続いて岩石学
work with geochemistry
地球化学を扱う
from the south
南から
The reference listed here
ここに記載されている参考文献
It's me who supervises some graduate students at National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学で大学院生を指導しているのは私です
Coupled with the cooperation with the Beijing Academy of Chinese Sciences
北京中国科学院との協力もあり
or co-advised graduate students
または共同指導を受けた大学院生
a series of work done
一連の作業が完了しました
Actually there are more
実際にはもっとあります
Tracking from the south of Tibet to the southeast
チベットの南から南東への追跡
Then the one in South Asia
それから南アジアのもの
Dark Thirteen can actually be tracked further south
ダーク 13 は実際にはさらに南に追跡できます
West of Mingnan
名南西部
then into Burma
その後ビルマへ
So I'm now a postdoctoral researcher
それで私は今博士研究員です
PhD researcher who works with me
私と一緒に働いている博士研究員
You know he is now
彼が今いるのは知っていますよね
This is the way to track southeast
こちらは南東へ向かう道です
Work in Myanmar
ミャンマーで働く
After arriving in Myanmar
ミャンマー到着後
You'll be able to do advanced traffic
高度なトラフィックを実行できるようになります
go on some field trips
野外旅行に行く
then take the time
それから時間をかけてください
Come back to work in the lab
研究室での仕事に戻ってください
A South Asian Andy Thirteen
南アジア人のアンディ 13 歳
or we say
または私たちは言います
Mianyan is more than 3000 kilometers along the river and lake
綿岩は川と湖に沿って3000キロ以上あります
Cotton rock cheap rose to
コットンロック格安ローズ
South China Sea
南海
On top of Sumatra in Indonesia
インドネシアのスマトラ島の頂上
Can
できる
we have now
私たちは今持っています
work has spread to
仕事が広がった
Sumatra went up
スマトラ島が上がった
Then it looks like the lake of Andy Thirteen
そうすれば、アンディ13の湖のように見えます
From South Asia actually across the Pamirs
南アジアからパミール高原を越えて
further west into iran
さらに西へイランへ
or the range where the elevated
または上昇した範囲
I'll take a moment to introduce you
ちょっとご紹介させていただきます
Students can make a face-to-face discussion
学生は対面でディスカッションを行うことができます
How did the address of Tibet evolve?
チベットの住所はどのように進化したのでしょうか?
Like this article, a north-south instant noodle is drawn
この記事のように南北のインスタントラーメンが描かれています
The north-south instant noodles are probably this place
南北インスタントラーメンはおそらくここ
Draw a north-south instant noodle
南北のインスタントラーメンを描く
Say from India to the interior of Tibet
インドからチベット奥地まで言う
or how the interior of Asia might change
あるいはアジアの内陸がどう変化するか
from 65 million years ago
6500万年前から
There is the time when the new generation begins
新しい世代が始まる時が来ます
Then it gradually changed to what it is today
その後徐々に変化して今の形になりました
Tibet draws a north-south instant noodle
チベットが南北に描くインスタントラーメン
It's the south, it's the north
それは南です、それは北です
So this side is India and this side is Asia
つまり、こちら側はインドで、こちら側はアジアです
we guess or we speculate
私たちは推測するか推測します
Or we propose a model that says
あるいは、次のようなモデルを提案します。
it should look like this
このように見えるはずです
First two plates collide
最初の 2 つのプレートが衝突する
Then there is a green plate in front called
すると手前に緑色のプレートがあります。
Ocean Plate of Tethyslan
テティスランの海洋プレート
One action is that it has to be detached first
アクションの 1 つは、最初に切り離す必要があることです。
stripped off
剥ぎ取られた
Because after the two road-grabbing plates collided,
2枚の路面掴み板が衝突した後、
This heavier oceanic plate
この重い海洋プレートは
will fall off
落ちます
Like a drag gong called a Slap Breakup
スラップブレイクアップというドラッグのゴングのように
The road and Asia began to collide violently
道路とアジアが激しく衝突し始めた
after a violent collision
激しい衝突の後
Asia's plate is relatively soft
アジアのプレートは比較的柔らかい
The Indian plate is colder and harder
インドのプレートは冷たくて硬い
So it will cause the Asian board to drill the board
つまり、アジアの理事会が理事会に穴を開けることになるでしょう
Then it became like this
そしたらこうなりました
stubborn
頑固
Because of the balance of gravity
重力のバランスのせいで
Then something sinks under the Asian plate
そして何かがアジアのプレートの下に沈む
drag the gong and sink
ゴングを引きずって沈む
This action we call
私たちが呼ぶこのアクションは、
Root Foundering
ルートファウンダー
The Chinese translation seems to be called to follow
中国語訳は以下のように呼ばれているようです
or split function
または分割機能
So we think that during the formation of Tibet
したがって、私たちはチベットの形成中に次のように考えています。
Breakup with a special thought section
特別思想部との決別
Then there is a thickened asian plate
それから分厚いアジアのプレートがあります
The role of the dismantling of the Asian plate
アジアプレート解体の役割
In the end it became what it is today
結局今のような形になりました
Of course, there is no way to talk about the process of the department in detail.
もちろん、部門のプロセスについて詳しく話すことはできません。
That
それか
When the actual Breakup happened
実際の解散が起こったとき
Probably in the address history
おそらくアドレス履歴にあると思います
fifty million years ago
5千万年前
Fifty MA occurred at that time
このとき50MA発生
because how do we know
なぜならどうやって知ることができるのでしょうか
Because we found a lot of records of magma activity on it
マグマ活動の記録がたくさん見つかったので
So using these records of magmatic activity
したがって、これらのマグマ活動の記録を使用すると、
And come out sticky controls are all this time
そして、今回はスティッキーコントロールが出てきます
So draw a picture of instant noodles at that time
なので当時のインスタントラーメンの絵を描いてください
The detailed diagram is probably at this level
詳細図はおそらくこのレベル
At that time, the upper and lower plates or the earth's crust are sucked
その際、上下のプレートや地殻が吸い込まれます。
or the lithosphere is not thick
あるいはリソスフェアが厚くない
relatively thin
比較的薄い
So there's an asthenosphere of convection coming up
つまり、対流のアセノスフェアが起こっているということです
That sounds too professional
それは専門的すぎるように聞こえます
But the so-called time when
しかし、いわゆるその時が来ると、
It causes the geochemistry of magmatism
マグマ活動の地球化学を引き起こす
will also change with
によっても変わります
For example, the 50 million years just mentioned
たとえば、先ほど述べた 5,000 万年
Fifty million years of this virtue
この美徳が5千万年続く
But we can draw a noodle diagram
しかし、麺の図を描くことはできます。
because we're using the time stamp as a guide
タイムスタンプをガイドとして使用しているため、
That's sixty million years
それは6000万年です
fifty million years
5千万年
forty million years
四千万年
thirty million years
3000万年
we are south of west
私たちは西の南にいます
Specimens dating back 60 million years can be collected
6000万年前の標本が採取可能
50 million year old specimen
5000万年前の標本
40 million year old specimen
4000万年前の標本
That picture is right
その写真は正しいです
There is a detailed earth year for the geochemical analysis to see
地球化学分析で確認できる詳細な地球年があります。
Since 50 million years
5000万年前から
The nature of the created igneous rocks or magmatic activities is different.
生成される火成岩やマグマ活動の性質が異なる
It has different Lensinum etubium
異なるレンシナム etubium があります
The Racial change
人種の変化
There are different C variations for these two elements
これら 2 つの要素にはさまざまな C バリエーションがあります。
This has a change that tells us that
これには次のような変化があります。
The chemistry of the magma that formed was different
形成されたマグマの化学的性質が異なっていた
My earlier narration said
私の以前のナレーションはこう言いました
Magma chemistry reflects differences in plate tectonic environments
マグマの化学的性質はプレートテクトニクス環境の違いを反映する
right
右
The Bagel knowledge of some research and geochemistry told us that
いくつかの研究と地球化学に関するベーグルの知識は、私たちに次のことを教えてくれました。
The chemistry that produces this ingredient in this way
この成分をこのように生成する化学
The chemical nature of the magma is a signal that the crust is beginning to thicken
マグマの化学的性質は、地殻が厚くなり始めていることを示す信号です
That is, since 50 million years ago
つまり5000万年前から
The crust in the south of Tibet began to gradually thicken
チベット南部の地殻は徐々に厚くなり始めた
So the pen quality of the element in the magma it creates
したがって、それが作成するマグマ内の要素のペンの品質
or its protogeochemical signature
またはその原始地球化学的特徴
will follow the magma from 50 million years ago
5000万年前のマグマをたどる
are different
異なっています
May I
いいですか
So if we go back to this cartoon
それでこの漫画に戻ると
just tell us
教えてください
India and Asia collide
インドとアジアが衝突
hit hard
ハードヒット
this is cold and hard
これは寒くて大変です
also hardness plate
硬度プレートも
This is relatively warm and soft
比較的暖かくて柔らかいです
The Asian plate begins to thicken
アジアプレートが厚くなり始める
So this one looks thin
だからこれは薄く見えます
This Asian plate is gradually thickening
このアジアのプレートは徐々に厚くなっています
thickened to what it is today
今日のように厚くなっています
today's appearance
今日の様子
Why are we talking about crust thickening?
なぜ地殻の肥厚について話しているのですか？
because under Tibet
チベットの下だから
There is currently the last continental crust on Earth
現在、地球上には最後の大陸地殻があります
if you remember
覚えていれば
My classmates in high school may all remember it clearly
高校の同級生はみんな鮮明に覚えているかもしれない
earth science textbook
地球科学の教科書
I told us that the average thickness of the continental crust is
大陸地殻の平均的な厚さは
40 kilometers, right?
40キロですよね？
The thickness of the crust below Tibet is
チベットの下の地殻の厚さは
Average to twice the thickness of the Earth's crust
平均して地殻の2倍の厚さ
after it reaches 80 kilometers
80キロに到達したら
So all geological issues in Tibet
つまり、チベットの地質学的問題はすべて
or anyone who constructs evolutionary problems must explain
あるいは進化論の問題を構築する人は説明しなければなりません
why it can thicken up to 80 km
なぜ厚さは最大80kmにもなるのか
What we know from the geochemical evidence
地球化学的証拠からわかっていること
50 eight years later
8年後の50歳
On cue that he started Dico started thickening
彼が始めたのを合図に、ディコは太り始めました
So this thickening time is
したがって、この濃厚化時間は
After a lot, you can go all the way to today's 70 to 80 kilometers
だいぶ経って今日の70～80キロまで行ける
There will be a special research area when the first section is thickened
最初のセクションが厚くなると、特別な研究エリアが存在します
This particular research has a special jargon
この特定の研究には特別な専門用語が含まれています
called aedakites
アエダカイトと呼ばれる
Chinese called aedakite
中国ではアエダカイトと呼ばれる
When we were in 2003
2003 年の頃
First found in the south of Tibet
チベット南部で初めて発見された
The special research boundary melted by this thickened crust
厚くなった地殻によって溶けた特別研究の境界
made a report
報告をしました
aedakite that thing
アエダカイトあれ
such a report
そのような報告
Later in that geotubes it was quoted that
そのジオチューブの後半で、次のように引用されました。
This is a very important new discovery in research and inspection
これは研究分野における非常に重要な新発見です
new discovery
新しい発見
So I got this from that wikipedia
それでウィキペディアからこれを取得しました
the thing that leaked
漏れたもの
Emphasis on aedakite
アエダカイトの強調
Inside that photo bag where continents collided
大陸が衝突したあの写真バッグの中
Thin barriers can appear
薄い障壁が現れることがある
The cited reference is 4
引用文献は4です
This is our article
これは私たちの記事です
when i was in class
私が授業中に
often take this thing out
よくこれを取り出します
Take it out and show it to the students
それを取り出して生徒たちに見せてください
Then do a little more introduction
それからもう少し紹介してください
It was a study class at that time
その時は勉強会でした
can be more detailed
より詳細に説明できます
But if you are naughty, just say
でも、もしあなたがいたずらなら、言ってください
Can Wikipedia be edited by yourself?
ウィキペディアは自分で編集できますか?
So he said the teacher is filled in by yourself
それで彼は、先生はあなた自身で埋められると言った
I really didn't fill it in
本当に埋めてなかった
You are welcome to go up and have a look
ぜひ上がって覗いてみてください
If you remember Adkite
アドカイトを覚えているなら
but
しかし
Please don't delete this one on purpose
これを意図的に削除しないでください
The journal is called Geology
その雑誌は「地質学」という名前です
I just said that the American Area Society
私は先ほど言いました、アメリカ地域協会は
Special journals have made special statistics
特別なジャーナルが特別な統計を作成しました
past eleven or eleven years
過去11年か11年
The so-called highly sighted paper
所謂highly sighted paper
We have exactly two articles including that one
その記事を含めてちょうど 2 つの記事があります
The other one was made by teacher Zhu Meiwei just now
もう一つは朱美偉先生が先ほど作ったものです
What's in a doctoral dissertation
博士論文の内容
two in
2つで
Inside of the top three reference names for each year
各年の上位 3 つの参照名の内側
So in this big pie chart
この大きな円グラフでは
Taiwan is squeezed into this small, very small gorge
台湾はこの小さな、とても小さな峡谷に押し込まれています
this is bragging
これは自慢です
so try not to talk
だから話さないようにしてください
In addition to studying the South Asian Andy Thirteen
南アジアのアンディ13世の研究に加えて、
Since you have done so much telling the truth
あなたは真実を伝えるためにたくさんのことをしてきたので、
telltale work can
証拠となる仕事ができる
In fact, it is helping us to do another
実際、それは私たちが別のことをするのに役立っています
Things related to the research and development of South Asian terrane structure
南アジアの地形構造の研究開発に関すること
It's the one here who rises from the mountain
山から登ってくるのはここにいる人だ
With the climate of this Southeast Asia
この東南アジアの気候と
and even the development of the river system
そして河川系の発展さえも
have a very close relationship
非常に密接な関係がある
It is the development map of today's water system
現在の水道システムの展開図です
But in the past in the history of Earth Day
しかし、アースデイの歴史の中で、
In this case, before the Indian collision
この場合、インド衝突前
Isn't there an ancient ocean ahead?
この先には太古の海があるのではないか？
That ancient ocean is called special breeding
その古代の海は特別な繁殖と呼ばれています
So before India collided
つまりインドが衝突する前
I believe there are many rivers here
ここにはたくさんの川があると思います
Actually it's not east
実は東ではないんです
Instead, it flows westward into this ancient Mediterranean
その代わりに、この古代地中海に西に流れ込みます。
Or specially kept inside
または特別に屋内に保管されている
It is because of this collision that the ocean
この衝突のせいで海は
This ancient ocean is closed
この太古の海は閉ざされている
Then the terrain rises
すると地形が盛り上がってきます
So all new rivers go east
したがって、新しい川はすべて東に流れます
or flow southeast
または南東に流れる
So there is a topic to study that
それで、それを研究するトピックがあります
The collision process from no collision to the beginning of the collision to the current situation
衝突なしから衝突開始、現在の状況に至るまでの衝突過程
How did the major water systems and major rivers in Southeast Asia develop?
東南アジアの主要な水系と主要な河川はどのようにして発展したのでしょうか?
This can be done as a so-called South to think
これはいわゆる南として考えることができます
The environment from the original to the grade is called South
オリジナルからグレードまでの環境をサウスと呼びます
Related research from the original meeting
元の会議での関連研究
Because of the dissolution of the plateau, it is in the off sea of ​​Southeast Asia
高原が崩壊したため、東南アジアの沖合にある
Now there are so many young Chen Jiwu
今では若いチェン・ジウがたくさんいる
The young Chen Jiwu has a lot of facts to do related research work
若いChen Jiwuは、関連する研究活動を行うための多くの事実を持っています
The truth in this Chen Jiwu or the truth from the time of marriage
このチェン・ジウの真実か結婚当時の真実か
There is a proper term called Detrital Zochron
デトリタルゾクロンという適切な用語があります
Chinese is called the truth of debris
中国語は瓦礫の真実と呼ばれます
It's the confessions from the time of the relatives
親戚の時の告白です
So we can go and study the age of the detritus' truth
それで私たちはパン粉の中にある真実の時代を研究しに行くことができます
Analyze its age, analyze its Hartung number
年齢を分析し、Hartung 数を分析します
and trace its source
そしてその源をたどる
Let's discuss the process of the river's pro-time transportation and accumulation
川の長期輸送と蓄積のプロセスについて話しましょう
Right on the plateau we can study the stones on the plateau
高原のすぐ上で、高原の石を研究することができます
So struck
とても衝撃的でした
after that
その後
The main river will be developed under the plateau
本流は台地の下に開発される
grab the sand inside
中の砂を掴む
Go study the debris notice inside
中にある瓦礫の通知を調べてみましょう
Then the mountain can be compared with the mountain
そうすれば、山と山を比較することができます
Can see a lot of things that others can't see
他の人には見えないものがたくさん見える
or something that no one has seen before
あるいは誰も見たことのないもの
In the materials I gave you again, an oiler said
もう一度お渡しした資料の中で、油屋さんはこう言っています。
A few grains of notice to make mountains
山を作るための小さな気づきの粒
It's about this story
この話のことです
At that time, this one had very long hair
この時は髪がとても長かったです
very elegant graduate student
とてもエレガントな大学院生
Wearing a very red and very bright coat on Tibet
チベットでとても赤くてとても明るいコートを着ている
This is Yalu Tibetan wood pulp
これはヤルーチベット木材パルプです
Then ask his seniors and sisters to help him collect specimens
次に、先輩や妹たちに標本の収集を手伝ってもらいます。
I picked some sand and came back
砂を拾って戻ってきました
Then analyze the debris notice inside
次に内部の瓦礫の通知を分析します
Then find a way to use
それから使用方法を見つけてください
For that boundless imagination
その無限の想像力のために
What kind of connections are there in the middle?
真ん中にはどんなつながりがあるのでしょうか？
There's a lot of fun in there
そこにはたくさんの楽しみがあります
But I can't tell you carefully
でも丁寧に教えてもらえない
in order to track down this thing
このことを追跡するために
So we ran down the hill
それで私たちは丘を駆け下りました
good
良い
India can't go to India
インドはインドに行けない
So only with Indians India
だからインド人だけインド
while collaborating on this
これに協力しながら
The lower reaches of the Yarlung Zangmu River are called
ヤルンザンムー川の下流は、
brahmaputra r.
ブラマプトラ R.
if you remember to do
覚えていれば
I couldn't remember it at first
最初は思い出せなかった
English is called Bama Putra
英語ではBama Putraといいます。
Bama Putra is this
バマ・プトラはこれです
one of the most important rivers in this place
この場所で最も重要な川の一つ
Then go east and enter the Irrawaddy River
それから東に進み、イラワジ川に入ります。
Then go east and enter into
それから東に進んで中に入ります
A series of Southeast Asian personnel that river
川を渡る一連の東南アジア人員
This is what our work looks like in the Irrawaddy
これがイラワジで働く私たちの姿です
none of the jobs
どの仕事もありません
It was this girl who knocked the stone hard
石を強く叩いたのはこの女の子でした
Then in the Irrawaddy River to pick
それからイラワジ川で採集します
sand
砂
Finally we now build
ついに構築します
good that data base
データベースはいいですね
Along this South Asia's Mount Iss
この南アジアのイス山に沿って
we picked a lot of that
私たちはそれをたくさん選びました
the hard rock from the middle
途中からハードロック
analyze the age of its telltale stone
その証拠となる石の年代を分析する
with the host
ホストと一緒に
The one that also analyzes rocks
岩石も分析するもの
Geochemistry Moderator
地球化学モデレータ
then follow this river
それからこの川をたどってください
major river system
主要な河川系
Then next to the water system of the water system
続いて水系の水系の次へ
The sand or the bottom that deposits locally inside
内部に局所的に堆積した砂や底
Mined a lot of cave stones
洞窟石をたくさん採掘した
I hope that the research on the mountain and the mountain can be coordinated
山と山の研究が連携できるといいですね
Look up and down or research this from Softs to Think
上下に調べたり、Softs to Think から調べたりしてください
Zhaoshantai is deep and the one received by Boshi at the bottom of the mountain
趙山台は深く、山の麓で法師が受け取ったもの
that thing that was recorded
記録されていたあのこと
This is my first grad student to tell the truth
本当のことを言うのは私にとって初めての大学院生です
Xiao Tang's work team of graduate students who just graduated this summer
この夏卒業したばかりのXiao Tangの卒業制作チーム
Myanmar made some fun stuff
ミャンマーは面白いものを作りました
but i can't go on
でも続けられない
Because I'm going to go into Topic 2
トピック 2 に入りますので、
Otherwise I take up too much time
そうしないと時間がかかりすぎる
The second theme is after we have done some work here
2 番目のテーマは、ここでいくつかの作業を行った後です。
I think we should go west to do some comparative work
比較研究をするために西に行ったほうがいいと思います
The most important reason why contrast works is that
コントラストが機能する最も重要な理由は次のとおりです。
As I said earlier this is a mature crash photo seatbelt
先ほども言いましたが、これは成熟した衝突写真のシートベルトです
It started to collide about 60 million years ago
約6000万年前に衝突が始まった
Mature banging takes big tits
成熟した叩いて巨乳を取る
there is a lot to study
勉強することがたくさんあります
But it has a very important disadvantage
しかし、それには非常に重要な欠点があります
The downside is the record early in the collision
欠点は衝突初期の記録だ
Overshadowed by later or later records
後の記録によって影が薄れてしまう
or was destroyed
あるいは破壊された
so many steps
とてもたくさんのステップ
Because I can't find it here or I can't see it completely
ここでは見つからない、または完全に見えないため
We just want to find the west sky
ただ西の空を見つけたいだけ
This is a younger, more initial collision state
これはより若い、より初期の衝突状態です。
In that place we can find records of the early days of the continental continental collision
そこには大陸衝突の初期の記録が残っている。
Finally, I hope to combine the states of these two different periods together.
最後に、これら 2 つの異なる時代の状態を組み合わせてみたいと思います。
we'll have a chance to see the collision state start
衝突状態が始まるのを確認する機会があります
and then until the evolution to the mature stage
そして成熟期への進化まで
It was a very simple idea when designing this time
今回デザインするときはとてもシンプルな発想でした
After doing it for a few years now, I realize that's not the case at all.
数年やってみて、全然そんなことないことに気づきました。
But I can't tell you the details
でも詳しくは言えません
I still have to tell you
まだあなたに言わなければなりません
Our logic is designed like this
私たちのロジックは次のように設計されています
And then funded by Congress's court program
そして議会の法廷プログラムによって資金提供された
It's a good thing that teacher Lu Luoquan didn't come today.
今日は盧洛泉先生が来なくて良かったです。
Otherwise he might condemn me
そうでなければ彼は私を非難するかもしれない
What I want to do is these two mountains or these two large plateaus
私がやりたいのはこの二つの山 あるいはこの二つの大きな高原
can we do one thing
一つ何かやってもいいですか
It is to use a story to describe the evolution of these two industries
これら 2 つの業界の進化を説明するためにストーリーを使用することです
The Tibetan Plateau next to this system
この星系の隣にあるチベット高原
The country over there is called the CIA Plateau
あそこの国はCIAプラトーと呼ばれています
It's Gao Jiasuo plus Iran plus Anatolia
高嘉蘇プラスイランプラスアナトリアです
He is called CIA by name
彼はCIAと名前で呼ばれています
Koken
高研
People can write Shuang Cheng Ji
人々はShuang Cheng Jiを書くことができます
A Tale of Two Cities
二都物語
we might be able to
私たちにはできるかもしれない
I have a pattern called A Tale of Two Pathos
「A Tale of Two Pathos」というパターンがあります
to this place
この場所へ
can think of something right now
今すぐ何かを考えることができる
something to do with history
歴史に関係する何か
in fact
実際には
Many concepts related to Greek mythology
ギリシャ神話に関連する多くの概念
There are many stories in it
その中にはたくさんの物語が詰まっています
words like here
ここのような言葉
Immediately thought of Persia
すぐにペルシアのことを思い出した
Because from Iran to Anatolia
なぜならイランからアナトリアまで
They are actually of the Persian race.
彼らは実際にはペルシャ人種です。
Then this picture is for you to see
それでは、この写真をご覧ください
Map of Alexander the Great
アレクサンダー大王の地図
if you remember
覚えていれば
the words of that hollywood movie a few years ago
数年前のあのハリウッド映画の言葉
so here we go
それでは行きましょう
to iran
イランへ
Immediately see a lot of Persian architecture
すぐにたくさんのペルシャ建築を見ることができます
Tehran is the capital of Iran
テヘランはイランの首都です
Tehran is a very ugly city
テヘランはとても醜い街だ
Then it is very discouraged to go
それなら行くのはとても気が滅入ります
but tehran has one
しかしテヘランにはそれがある
iran has one
イランには1つある
The current second largest city is Isfahan
現在第二の都市はイスファハンです
in the south
南部で
Isfahan is a very important
イスファハンはとても重要な場所です
The ancient city of Persia
ペルシャの古代都市
Then the Iranians themselves said
するとイラン人自身がこう言った
istan represents half of the world
イスタンは世界の半分を代表する
Half of the world
世界の半分
There are many places worth visiting in the middle
真ん中には訪れる価値のある場所がたくさんあります
Then this is taken from the webpage in Ma Youyou's private plan
これは Ma Youyou のプライベート プランの Web ページから抜粋したものです
So if you want to broadcast something about Persia
ペルシャに関する何かを放送したい場合
other than music
音楽以外の
In fact, on the webpage of Ma Youyou's private plan
実際、馬友佑のプライベートプランのウェブページには
There are many beautiful photos
美しい写真がたくさんあります
Professional-grade photos we can't get
私たちには得られないプロレベルの写真
when you go to iran
イランに行ったら
Immediately encountered a lot of different things
早速、色々な事に遭遇しました
This photo is on the poster
この写真はポスターに載っています
You'll see reports on CNN or BDC
CNN または BDC のレポートが表示されます
something very different
何かとても違うもの
There are very, very friendly fellow villagers
とてもとてもフレンドリーな村人たちがいます
very kind people
とても親切な人々
have very blue sky
空がとても青い
There is very sour oil that is not very tasty
油が酸っぱくてあまり美味しくない
and then there's korankin, which is everywhere
そしてコーランキンがどこにでもいます
And then you'll often run into some desert climate stuff
そして、砂漠気候の問題に遭遇することもよくあります
so there is a hot sun
だから暑い太陽があります
But these when you have good geological phenomena can be seen
しかし、地質が良好な場合にはこれらの現象が見られます。
it doesn't matter
それは問題ではありません
I have many photos of Iran
イランの写真がたくさんあります
But I can't show you one by one
でも一つ一つお見せすることはできない
If you push further west in Iran
イランをさらに西に進めば
Arrived at the viaduct
高架橋に到着
This is the scenery of Daejiao Suo Mountain in spring
春の大角蘇山の風景です
very different from iran
イランとは大きく違う
above iran you see
イランの上に見えます
mostly desert climate stuff
主に砂漠気候のもの
then you get to the elevated
それから高台に着きます
you see a lot of green things
緑のものがたくさん見えます
The elevated mountain has something to do with Greek mythology
高い山はギリシャ神話と関係がある
Because there is a prome
プロメがあるので
Hughes fell here
ヒューズはここに落ちた
Prometheus is the movie from last year to the year before
プロメテウスは去年から一昨年にかけての映画です
I'm very interested
とても興味があります
Because of the relationship with the elevated
上級者との関係があるので、
The giant who was punished by Kanari
カナリに懲らしめられた巨人
The giant hand hangs on a cliff at the Great Elevated Station
大高架駅の崖に垂れ下がる巨大な手
The liver that accepts Lao Yin to eat him day after day
来る日も来る日もラオ・インを受け入れる肝臓
leaver
退職者
Is such that
そういうことですか
So when I went to the elevated station
それで高架駅に行ったとき
just try hard to find the cliff
頑張って崖を見つけてください
Check for Prometheus
プロメテウスを確認する
see a lot of beautiful scenery
美しい景色をたくさん見る
But without Prometheus
でもプロメテウスがいないと
But there are many beauties in elevated places
でも高いところには美しい人がたくさんいる
But not always so lucky
しかし、必ずしも幸運とは限りません
Like this aluminum one seems to like my look better
このアルミニウムのように、私の見た目がより気に入っているようです
Then push to the west and go quickly.
それから西に押して素早く進みます。
because my business should be coming soon
私の用事がもうすぐ始まるはずだから
to Türkiye
トゥルキエ行き
Türkiye has so many things to mention
トゥルキエには言及すべきことがたくさんあります
except address
住所以外
But I can only give you three examples
ただし、例として挙げられるのは 3 つだけです
show you this
これを見せてください
Servo project by Red Pit
Red Pitによるサーボプロジェクト
he ran to that from the west
彼は西からそこへ走った
Inside the Troy Coming Movie
映画『トロイの到来』の内側
The god of war who played the legend
伝説を演じた軍神
Akievez's movie
アキエベスの映画
watched several times
何度か見た
but what about the story
しかし、話はどうですか
If you are interested in
興味があれば
I'll talk to you later when we're free
後で暇になったら話しましょう
Then this place is actually
では、この場所は実は
Alishan's Great has a great relationship
阿里山大は素晴らしい関係を持っています
Your memorial to Turkey from the west
西からトルコへのあなたの記念碑
next to the sea of ​​love or greece
愛の海の隣、またはギリシャ
Especially the South China Sea along this sea of ​​insects
特にこの昆虫の海沿いの南シナ海
i have been to iran
私はイランに行ってきました
you see a lot
たくさん見ていますね
Alishan, what was left behind when Alishan came to the earth
阿里山、阿里山が地球に来たときに残したもの
Historic sites
史跡
very very spectacular special
とてもとても素晴らしいスペシャル
you can see a lot
たくさん見ることができます
But apart from these two movies
しかし、この2本の映画とは別に、
Another thing that is more important to me is this mountain
私にとってもう一つ大切なものはこの山です
this mountain is a volcano
この山は火山です
The name of the mountain is Mong Aralats
山の名前はモン・アララツです
Aralats is a holy mountain
アララツ山は聖なる山です
Two Holy Mountains of Meat in Islam and Christianity
イスラム教とキリスト教における肉の二つの聖なる山
This way you will think it is very troublesome
こうなるととても面倒だと思われるでしょう
I also know that probably in Turkey
おそらくトルコでもそうだと思います
The easternmost country is Armenia
最東端の国はアルメニアです
Near the border with Turkey
トルコとの国境付近
is in the bible
聖書の中にあります
When the Great Flood Occurs in the Bible
聖書で大洪水が起こるとき
Where the Loya's Ark stands
ロヤの箱舟が立っている場所
We are going to study this mountain next year
私たちは来年この山を勉強するつもりです
So if someone signs up
したがって、誰かがサインアップすると、
consider
考慮
we this year
私たちは今年
we are here today
私たちは今日ここにいます
The place that did the work is here
作業を行った場所はここです
in the southeast of Türkiye
トゥルキエの南東にある
It's on the border of Syria and Iraq.
シリアとイラクの国境にあります。
almost never go
ほとんど行かない
If the United States goes to fight Syria
もしアメリカがシリアとの戦いに行ったら
Good thing he didn't hit
彼が当たらなくて良かった
so we're here to do a job
だから私たちは仕事をするためにここにいます
Be a geological phenomenon
地質学的現象であること
Next to this is Iraq, right?
この次はイラクですよね？
Iraq is two river basins
イラクには 2 つの河川流域がある
One of the powers of civilized speech
文明的な言論の力の一つ
This thing can be seen while running out of Türkiye
これはトゥルキエを使い果たしているときに見ることができます
This is the source or upstream of the six-shot bottom box
これは 6 ショット ボトム ボックスのソースまたは上流です
So you can do address stepping on my drug specimen here
だからここで私の薬物検体を踏んで住所を書いてください
At the same time, you can take pictures like this
同時にこんな写真も撮れます
So every time Mr. Peng said that I went to visit mountains and rivers everywhere
だから、彭さんが言うたびに、私は山や川を訪ねるためにどこへでも行きました。
still get money from congress
まだ議会から金もらってる
So that's the picture of Curtis in it
それがカーティスの写真です
A very important research address
非常に重要な研究アドレス
We call it Type Locality
それをタイプローカリティと呼びます
Because Türkiye has a special collision modeling effect
Türkiye には特別な衝突モデリング効果があるため
The Turks call it the Origin of Turkish Type
トルコ人はそれをトルコ活字の起源と呼んでいます
Turkic modeling movement
トルコのモデリング運動
because it's like cartoon books 84 million years ago
8,400万年前の漫画のようなものだから
between arabia and asia
アラビアとアジアの間
It's not just two big plates colliding
2枚の大きな板が衝突するだけではない
A lot of small microplates are added in the middle
途中に小さなマイクロプレートがたくさん追加されています
How did these microplates evolve?
これらのマイクロプレートはどのように進化したのでしょうか?
How did the action come about?
そのアクションはどのようにして生まれたのでしょうか？
How to do the interaction in the middle
途中でインタラクションを行う方法
Actually a lot of people have interesting address questions here
実際、多くの人がここで興味深い質問をしています
So I say it is actually a sandwich-style collision modeling movement
つまり、これは実際にはサンドイッチスタイルの衝突モデリングの動きであると言えます。
Except for two pieces of toast
トースト2枚を除いて
There is a lot of material in the middle
真ん中に具材がたっぷり入っています
waiting for a geologist to do it
地質学者がやってくれるのを待っている
to parse it
それを解析する
That's what it looks like now
それが今の様子です
It's all crowded together
全部混んでるよ
what to do in the middle
真ん中で何をするか
This separates his material piece by piece
これにより、彼のマテリアルが部分ごとに分離されます
Then tell us what's going on with the R&D here
それでは、ここの研究開発で何が起こっているのか教えてください
how to solve this place
この場所をどうやって解決するか
The so-called Tectonic Curse Rule in Geology
地質学におけるいわゆる地殻変動の法則
structural substance
構造物質
There are many, many issues worthy of research
研究する価値のある問題はたくさんあります
so we went on a raid
それで私たちは襲撃に行きました
The most important reason to work is to
働く最大の理由は、
think about researching this
これを研究することを考えてください
when setting up this plan
このプランを立てる際に
quickly
素早く
We design three main studies of that interest
私たちはその関心に関する 3 つの主要な研究を計画します
will study the work area
作業領域を勉強します
Study this northernmost point in Arabia
アラビアのこの最北端を研究してください
Crash Peak and lead north
クラッシュピークを越えて北へ向かう
we from the southeast of iran
私たちはイラン南東部の出身です
That is, near the border between Iran and Pakistan.
つまり、イランとパキスタンの国境付近です。
Then follow this to the northwest
それからこれを北西に進みます
Then finally go to the Protos of this CEIA
そしていよいよこのCEIAのプロトスへ
There are a lot of green things after the collision
衝突後は緑色のものがたくさんあります
research activity
研究活動
we want to do with these things
私たちはこれらのことをやりたいと思っています
Then new observations then suggest that we are in this place
その後、新たな観測により、私たちがこの場所にいることが示唆されます
have new explanations or models
新しい説明やモデルがある
I'll show you a few examples soon.
すぐにいくつかの例を紹介します。
This is my job as a PhD student
これが博士課程の学生としての私の仕事です
just along this usual place
いつものこの場所沿いに
I call it the Gangdi Stone Mountain in West Asia
私はそれを西アジアのガンディ石山と呼んでいます
Or the Antistone Mountains in West Asia
あるいは西アジアのアンシ山脈
OK so again
はい、それではもう一度
Let's do this first and pull this arabic block out
まずこれを実行して、このアラビア語のブロックを取り出しましょう
Then attribute the ancient Mediterranean or this special ocean to the
そして、古代の地中海、あるいはこの特別な海が、
Then Tedi Shiyang went north to do hidden work at that time
その後、テディ・シヤンは北へ向かい、当時隠された仕事を行っていました。
Here to create something like today's Gangdi Stone Mountain
ここで今日のガンディ石山のようなものを作成します
Let's get to know its time distribution
時間分布を知ろう
Then its rock-technical tailoring
そしてロックテクニカルな仕立て
and then to understand what the structure of the place looked like before the collision
そして衝突前のその場所の構造がどのようになっていたかを理解する
It takes a little hard work like this
こういうのはちょっと大変な作業が必要です
no one has done it before
これまで誰もやったことがない
My doctoral research
私の博士研究
This Gangdi stone mountain in West Asia has done a series of sampling and analysis work
西アジアにあるこのガンディ石山では、一連のサンプリングと分析作業が行われました。
This Gangdi Stone Mountain has a special name
このガン堤石山には特別な名前があります
Then there are two place names, the nameless is the lake
それから地名が二つあり、名前のないのは湖です
There is a big lake called Wumingye
五明渓という大きな湖があります
Dota is that name for a little trip here
Dota はここでの小旅行の名前です
Dota, the meaning of Persian painting is simply Dotr
Dota、ペルシャ絵画の意味は単に Dotr です
So it's easy to remember, the name of that city is Dotr
だから覚えやすいよ、その都市の名前はDotrです
I asked my Iranian friend why the city is called Dotr
イラン人の友人になぜこの街がドットルと呼ばれるのか聞いてみた
He said he didn't know, he couldn't take the test
彼は知らない、テストを受けられないと言いました
Anyway, this is the belt
とりあえずベルトはこれ
We have done the most detailed chronology and geochemistry ever done along this belt
私たちはこのベルトに沿ってこれまでに行われた中で最も詳細な年表と地球化学を行ってきました。
So the paper that published the lead film is the first one
つまり、主演映画を掲載した新聞が最初の新聞となる
There will be other things in the future
今後も色々あるだろうし
It can be discussed that the initial state of collision orogeny in this place
この場所での衝突造山運動の初期状態は次のとおりであると議論できます。
Then what is its boundary condition like?
では、その境界条件はどのようなものでしょうか？
More broadly, the so-called Zogras Origin
より広義には、いわゆるゾグラスオリジン
Because the mountain in Iran is called Zogras Mountain
イランの山はゾグラス山と呼ばれているので
This location is here, Zogras Mountain is here
この場所はここ、ゾグラス山はここ
If it corresponds to the east, it is the Himalayas in the south of Tibet.
東に相当するとすれば、チベット南部のヒマラヤ山脈です。
So the Himalayas in Iran are called Zogras
だからイランのヒマラヤ山脈はゾグラと呼ばれる
Then in a broad sense, we call it Zogras Origin
それを広い意味でゾグラスオリジンと呼びます。
It can also start to control or discuss this thing
このことについて管理したり議論したりし始めることもあります
The example given is that the end time of the delay event just now is not at the same time
与えられた例は、たった今の遅延イベントの終了時刻が同じではないことです。
This English name is Decronus
この英語名はデクロナスです
The translation of the mainland is called time-traversing through time
本土の翻訳はタイムトラベルと呼ばれます
It's just that the time is different
ただ時代が違うだけ
end time in the northwest
北西部の終了時間
Northwest of Iran is about 25 million years
イランの北西部は約2500万年前
The end of the event will be postponed around 25 million years
イベントの終結は約2500万年延期される
Then in the middle it becomes 15 million years
そうすると途中で1500万年になります
end around 15 million years
約1500万年後に終わる
It will be about 6 to 7 million years to the south
それは約600万年から700万年南にあります
So it ends time gradually towards the south
だから南に向かって徐々に時間が終わる
The local inspection means that the collision between Arabia and Eurasia in this place is
現地調査は、この場所でアラビアとユーラシアが衝突したことを意味します。
this place happened first
この場所が最初に起こった
After the occurrence, the Arab reaction will produce in reality
発生後、アラブの反応が現実に生じる
No Rotation in reverse time
逆時間での回転なし
come up
やってくる
Then turn off this special episode Shiyang in the middle
それから、この特別エピソードShiyangを途中でオフにしてください
then collide collide together
それから衝突します、一緒に衝突します
so this is the place
ここが場所です
The first constraint that prolongs the age of activity
活動期間を延長する最初の制約
Let's discuss the role of this collision
この衝突の役割について話し合いましょう
or that plate suture in this place is
それともこの場所のプレート縫合糸は
Diaclomus
ディアクロムス
Yes, that phenomenon
そう、あの現象
Then my other postdoctoral fellow is Peng Junneng
私のもう一人の博士研究員はPeng Junnengです
It's the postdoctoral fellow from Hong Kong
香港からの博士研究員です
Also did a lot of work locally
地元でも頑張ったね
and found something very interesting
そしてとても興味深いものを見つけました
Because of time constraints, I won't talk about him in particular.
時間の関係で彼については特に話しません。
As mentioned earlier, for example,
先ほども述べたように、たとえば、
we are in some special places
私たちはいくつかの特別な場所にいます
Do detailed work on specific issues
特定の問題について詳細な作業を行う
and then to solve
そして解決するために
The local or specific geological problem
局所的または特定の地質学的問題
But in the end I hope to be able to synthesize
でも最終的には合成できるようになりたいです
Jobs on the west side of the place vs. jobs on the east side
場所の西側の仕事と東側の仕事
plus the rest of asia
プラス残りのアジア
Included here includes jobs in South East Asia
ここには東南アジアの仕事も含まれます
From a more macro perspective
よりマクロな視点から見ると
Asian continent
アジア大陸
The process of evolution of the entire continental crust
大陸地殻全体の進化の過程
Because the continent of Asia is the largest in the history of the earth
アジア大陸は地球史上最大の大陸だから
Since the Avatar
アバター以来
Xianshen seat is since the beginning of the Five Generations
仙神席は五代の初めからある
That's about 540 million years ago
それは約5億4000万年前のことです
The most important is the new continental crust
最も重要なのは新しい大陸地殻です
place of growth
成長の場
Then my teacher Jiang Boming
それから私の先生、ジャン・ボミン
A lot of jobs that Asians are doing in the previous one
前職ではアジア人がやっていた仕事が多かった
Then we are now in this Tethyste generation
そして私たちは今このテチステ世代です
Or the follow-up work done in the East Tethyste generation
あるいは東部テチステ世代で行われたフォローアップの研究
Finally, you can hope that you can combine
最後に、組み合わせることができることを期待できます。
something related to this
これに関連した何か
Make a more macroscopic explanation of the whole of Asia
アジア全体をよりマクロ的に説明する
In it it's the finale of my end
その中で、それは私の終わりのフィナーレです
But the research is actually halfway through
しかし実際には研究は半分まで進んでいる
is from 2011
2011年からです
To be carried out until 2026
2026年まで実施予定
Chinese and English together
中国語と英語を併用
Pretty nice
かなりいい
2016 is now exactly in the middle of the third year
2016年もちょうど3年目の真ん中です
So it's less than two halves
つまり半分以下です
Another two and a half years to work
あと2年半働く
Maybe I can really sing the finale later
フィナーレは後で本当に歌えるかもしれない
So before singing the real finale
だから本当のフィナーレを歌う前に
Thinking of Bobby
ボビーを想う
The famous song is called Blood in the wind
有名な曲は「Blood in the Wind」という曲です
there is a line in it
そこに線があります
i borrow to be my end
私は私の終わりになるために借ります
說How many years can a mountain exist
說山は何年存在できるか
before it's washed away to the sea?
海に流される前に？
The answer is
答えは
Lowing in the wind
風に吹かれて低くなっている
I can't find the answer in minutes
数分以内に答えは見つからない
But we will continue to do our create research project
しかし、私たちは研究プロジェクトの作成を継続します
hope in the near future
近い将来の希望
I can introduce more things to you
もっといろいろ紹介できるよ
I'll stop here thank you
ここでやめておきます、ありがとう
Thanks
ありがとう
Thank you Mr. Zhang for this wonderful introduction
張さん、素晴らしい紹介をありがとう
And he has good timing
そして彼はタイミングが良い
It will be over in about 80 minutes
80分くらいで終わります
So we have a lot of time for Q&A
ですので、質疑応答の時間がたっぷりあります
The first comment is
最初のコメントは、
I seem to have chosen the wrong line
回線の選択を間違えたようです
I should learn the address from him
彼から住所を学ばなければなりません
that open scenery
開けたその景色
OK
OK
ok we open to
わかりました、オープンします
everyone can ask questions
誰もが質問することができます
good
良い
Then you use your microphone to
次に、マイクを使用して、
Press the green one
緑色のものを押してください
Teacher, can I ask you?
先生、聞いてもいいですか？
You just talked about this MD-43 in Asia
アジアでこの MD-43 について話しましたね
It was originally bent
もともと曲がっていた
Or because it was bent by the Indian continent
それともインド大陸によって曲がったからなのか
I thought he was smoother
もっとスムーズな人だと思ってた
Because India only squeezed after meeting
インドは会議後に絞っただけだから
When the Frenchman just said
フランス人がさっき言ったとき、
He escaped, but he didn't
彼は逃げたが、逃げなかった
If you escape, it's just not a squeeze.
逃げたらただの絞りではない。
No, escaping is another phenomenon
いいえ、逃げるのは別の現象です
It actually has something to do with the bending process.
実はこれには曲げ加工が関係しています。
He did come and escape
彼はやって来て逃げた
But the mechanism by which he escaped
しかし、彼が逃げたメカニズムは、
will escape time french
フランス語で時間を逃れます
we think they are wrong
私たちは彼らが間違っていると思います
Okay, thank you
大丈夫ありがとう
good
良い
that teacher
あの先生
Thank you for your introduction
ご紹介いただきありがとうございます
Because according to the three generations, the two
なぜなら、三世代によれば、二人は
Collision of different plate shapes
異なる形状のプレートの衝突
Well said
よく言った
That is, if the oceanic plates collide
つまり、海洋プレートが衝突すると、
I want to generate something like North or South America
北米か南米のようなものを生成したい
Andis Sanmai
安迪士三脈
This is the so-called rocky rivers and lakes
いわゆる岩だらけの川や湖です。
Nazagors or Turkine
ナザゴールまたはトルキン
Up-to-date on this last PhD study
この最後の博士号研究に関する最新情報
I have a curious
好奇心があります
I think Taiwan happens to be the same
台湾も同じだと思う
I have 600 better
私は600以上良いものを持っています
Ocean version, but where is the lava lake on our side?
海洋編ですがこちら側の溶岩湖はどこにあるのでしょうか？
There is a magma lake. The ocean mountain range is mainly a magma lake that travels to the island lake.
マグマ湖があり、海洋山脈は主にマグマ湖で島の湖に流れています。
Then if you go to the north, Chancellor Mountain, many people say it is a magma lake that continues to Ryukyu Island Lake
そして北に行くと宰相山、琉球島湖に続くマグマ湖だと言う人も多い
so there are still
まだあります
It's just that Taiwan's spatial scale is very small
ただ台湾の空間スケールは非常に小さいです
So there are certain difficulties in parsing, plus
したがって、解析には特定の困難があります。
The time scale is very short, and the step of Taiwan is about five or six million years ago
時間スケールは非常に短く、台湾の歩みは約500万年か600万年前です。
Compared with Tibet, Tibet is about 50 to 60 million years old
チベットと比較すると、チベットは約5,000万年から6,000万年前のものです。
Then its scale is 3,000 kilometers wide. I am more than 3,000 kilometers wide, and Taiwan is only about 300 kilometers long.
その規模は幅3,000キロメートル、私は幅3,000キロメートル以上ですが、台湾の長さはわずか約300キロメートルです。
So time and space belong to Tibet
つまり、時間と空間はチベットのものである
One-tenth, one Ode is missing, if one Ode is missing, it can be done in geology
10分の1、1オード不足、1オード不足なら地質学でできる
simulation possible
模擬可能
Space is easy to control, but time is very difficult to control, because the geological time is five or six million years
空間は制御するのが簡単ですが、地質時代の時間は500万年か600万年であるため、時間は制御するのが非常に困難です。
In chronology and dating, it is not easy to determine accurately
年代や年代を正確に判断することは容易ではありません
So Taiwan has a Taiwan problem
つまり台湾には台湾問題がある
I also accidentally did some Taiwanese work
うっかり台湾作品もやってしまいました
So if Mr. Peng invites me to come again in the future
だから、もし彭さんが私を誘ってくれたら、また来てください。
Next time I will tell you about Taiwan
次回は台湾についてお話します
But Taiwan does have
でも台湾にはあるんだよ
But there is no way to do a one-on-one parallel
しかし、1対1の並列を行う方法はありません
Contrast because of the problem of time and space
時間と空間の問題によるコントラスト
I am a teacher, but
私は教師ですが、
I had a question just now and I just forgot to say it
先ほど質問があったのですが、言い忘れてしまいました
If it's North America, the one you're talking about
それが北米なら、あなたが話しているのはそこです
Himalayan side huh? His lava dance is granite
ヒマラヤ側か? 彼の溶岩ダンスは花崗岩だ
The problem is we are thinking about Taiwan
問題は私たちが台湾のことを考えていることだ
Of course I know that the scale is much different, and
もちろんスケールが違うのは分かっていますが、
Because there is an order difference, and both North America and the Himalayas started more than 60 million years ago
順序に違いがあり、北アメリカとヒマラヤはどちらも 6,000 万年以上前に始まりました。
Your question is very very good and has been well thought out since I do this
あなたの質問は非常に優れており、これを行うときからよく考えられています
Because of time I can't speak too deeply
時間の関係であまり深くは話せませんが、
or too rigid
または硬すぎる
So simplifies skipping a lot of stuff
したがって、多くのことをスキップすることが簡素化されます
Many of the three Legis veins in North America are granite rocks
北米の 3 つのレジス脈の多くは花崗岩です
Yes, then Gandisan in Tibet
はい、それではチベットのガンディサンです
It is also mainly granite
こちらも主に花崗岩です
We call these flower steel rocks
私たちはこれらの花を鋼鉄の岩と呼んでいます
Qingluyan in volcanic petrology
火山岩石学における清凉岩
Qingluyan means
清凉燕とは
It wasn't created by a volcanic eruption to the surface
地表への火山の噴火によってできたものではありません
It is after a certain depth underground
地中にある程度の深さがあると
Slowly cools and turns into a green rock mass
ゆっくりと冷えて緑色の岩塊になります
And now it means to come to the surface
そして今、それは表面に現れることを意味します
like the example of tibetan kandishan
チベットのカンディシャンの例のように
We know Candisian was underground
私たちはカンディシア人が地下にいたことを知っています
It's underground, some places are 20 kilometers deep
それは地下にあり、深さ20キロメートルの場所もあります
formed a stone
石を形成した
Now it's on the surface
今は表面に出ています
so tell us
だから教えてください
When Tibet was colliding with Taiwan's depth
チベットが台湾の深部と衝突したとき
20 kilometers thick on the surface
地表の厚さは20キロメートル
The stone that covered it has been eroded away
それを覆っていた石は侵食されてしまった
Now it's all moved to the sea
今はすべて海に移されています
move into the bay of bengal
ベンガル湾に移動する
or other grade powder inside
または内部の他のグレードの粉末
for example
例えば
So it puts the green dew rock under the ground
それで緑の露の岩を地面の下に置きます
Flower dry rock exposure
花乾岩 曝露地
come on the surface
表面に出てくる
Very different from this is that the Andes are in South America
これと大きく異なるのは、アンデス山脈が南米にあることです。
The gate volcanoes of the Andes are all extrusive rocks
アンデスのゲート火山はすべて突き出た岩石です
called Kanak rocks
カナック岩と呼ばれる
So it's a volcanic rock
つまり火山岩です
So there should be a lot of dew rocks under it
だからその下には露岩がたくさんあるはずだ
something like granite
花崗岩のようなもの
but not yet exposed to the surface
しかしまだ表面には露出していない
Then to the example of Iran
次にイランの例に移ります
we actually see the same thing
私たちは実際に同じものを見ています
Inside the Andes Mountains in West Asia, Iran
西アジア、イランのアンデス山脈内
We are the young underbelly
私たちは若い底辺です
The young samurai compared to the one at the initial stage
若侍と初期との比較
So its body and wave stone are not so powerful
そのため本体と波動石はそれほど強力ではありません
So that UDMA there
UDMAがそこにあるということ
The magma fire in West Asia I just mentioned
先ほど述べた西アジアのマグマ火災
extrusive rock
突き出た岩
like the andes example
アンデスの例のように
So the difference between the entire Tibet and the Iranian viaduct is
つまり、チベット全体とイランの高架橋の違いは次のとおりです。
this is mature
これは成熟した
So its average altitude is 4500 meters high
つまり、平均標高は4500メートルです
means it is set high
高く設定されていることを意味します
During the high stage
ハイステージ中
At the same time there are many things on the surface
同時に表面には多くのものが存在します
The cover is smashed
カバーが潰れてます
was moved to sea
海に移された
to the west in the iranian caucasus
イランのコーカサスの西にある
Its average altitude is only 1000 meters high
平均高度はわずか1000メートルです
The plateau is only 1000 meters high
高原の高さはわずか1000メートルです
So it's a younger version of that dirty
つまり、それはその汚いものの若いバージョンです
so it's just starting to melt
だからそれはちょうど溶け始めている
Peeling isn't that great
ピーリングはそれほど良くない
And the wind in that place is not like the wind in the Indian Ocean
そしてその場所の風はインド洋の風とは違います
so not so much moisture
湿気はそれほど多くないので
erosion the degree of surface erosion
侵食 表面侵食の程度
much lighter than the east
東よりずっと軽い
I have an answer do you have a question
答えはありますが、質問はありますか
Thank you, teacher
ありがとう、先生
Our South Australian Edition
南オーストラリア州版
Does that count?
それはカウントされますか?
South Australia
南オーストラリア
electric eye
電気の目
collision collision
衝突衝突
So the Great South Australia or
それで、グレート・サウス・オーストラリアか、
you to telugu country
あなたはテルグ国へ
won't you see district nine
第9地区を見ませんか
Marble, right?
大理石ですよね？
I saw a lot of people in the prison area are very powerful
刑務所エリアで多くの人が非常に強力であるのを見ました
Dungeon area
ダンジョンエリア
said
言った
severe deformation
激しい変形
Monolithic not rigid deformation
モノリスは剛体変形ではありません
Yes or no
はい、もしくは、いいえ
It deformed at a high temperature and pressure
高温高圧で変形してしまう
If we push the pressure to the depth
圧力を奥まで押し込めば
It should be a stone 10 kilometers underground
地下10キロの石のはずだ
it produces that deformation
それがその変形を生み出す
Therefore, in the Taroko National Pressure Industry Co., Ltd.
したがって、太魯閣国圧産業では
Many rocks are about 10 kilometers underground
多くの岩石は地下約10キロメートルにあります
Then because of the collision with Zhaoshan
その後、趙山と衝突したため、
Then Taishan and then surface wave time
それから泰山、そして表面波の時間
now brought to the surface
今表面化した
seen by us
私たちから見た
The mechanism is much the same
仕組みはほぼ同じです
who
WHO
Hello teacher, thank you teacher for your wonderful speech
こんにちは、先生、素晴らしいスピーチをありがとう
what i want to ask is
私が聞きたいのは
as the teacher said at the beginning
先生が最初に言ったように
The scale of the teacher's research is very large
先生の研究の規模はとても大きいです
But throughout the speech
しかし、スピーチ全体を通じて、
Always comparing Tibet with the CIA
いつもチベットとCIAを比較する
However, what I want to ask the teacher here is to say
ただ、ここで先生に聞きたいのは、
Then in such a large-scale comparison
このような大規模な比較では
There are some
幾つかある
Maybe I don't know it's a violation of influence
それが影響力の侵害であることを私は知らないかもしれません
or have a major impact
または大きな影響を与える
May I ask how do you get rid of this kind of research?
この種の研究をどのようにして排除するのか聞いてもいいですか？
For example, just now you mentioned
例えば、今おっしゃいましたね
Turkish researchers put their place
トルコの研究者が自らの地位を確立
called a Türkiye shape
テュルキエ形状と呼ばれる
There are many small plates in the middle
真ん中には小さなお皿がたくさんあります
then it's like a sandwich
それならサンドイッチのようなものです
Then how can you say
じゃあどう言えばいいの？
The Turkish one can be used as
トルコのものは次のように使用できます
Early model of Tibet
チベットの初期モデル
Could it be Türkiye because of those little plates in the middle
真ん中にある小さな皿があるので、これはトゥルキエでしょうか？
So his whole future
つまり彼の未来全体が
His development is actually different from that of Tibet.
彼の発展は実際にはチベットの発展とは異なります。
Two stories, so let's say
2 つの物語があるので、言ってみましょう
this place
この場所
If you're excluding the model of that sandwich
そのサンドイッチのモデルを除外する場合
would you do this
これをしますか
that if you want
あなたが望むならそれ
Why do you feel like these factors
なぜこれらの要因のように感じますか
You can choose and exclude, thank you
選択したり除外したりできます、ありがとう
Your question is the stuff I'm going to write a thesis on
あなたの質問は私がこれから論文を書こうとしている内容です
so ask him to put you in place
だから彼にあなたをその場に置いてくれるように頼んでください
There's really no way to make a direct comparison.
実際には直接比較する方法はありません。
there are many in the middle
真ん中にたくさんあります
I have a slide in front of me
目の前に滑り台があります
There are many similarities
類似点がたくさんあります
many similarities
多くの類似点
But in fact there are more differences
しかし実際にはもっと多くの違いがあります
It should be as simple as we think
それは私たちが考えるのと同じくらいシンプルであるべきです
want its similarities
類似点が欲しい
But after doing this work
しかし、この作業を行った後、
In fact, finding the differences may be more important
実際には、違いを見つけることの方が重要かもしれません
that needs an explanation
それは説明が必要です
or a place worthy of study
あるいは研究に値する場所
So there is really no way to make a professional comparison between the two things.
したがって、この 2 つを専門的に比較する方法は実際にはありません。
Then there are a lot of details in the middle
それから真ん中にたくさんの詳細があります
i can't speak
私は話せません
Or I'm doing something related right now
あるいは、今それに関連することをやっている
Eventually is what you point out
結局のところ、あなたが指摘することは
there's something we're going to do
私たちがやろうとしていることがある
Thanks
ありがとう
Hello, professor, what I want to ask is
こんにちは、教授、聞きたいのは
May I ask that the mountain on the light barrier plateau can
堰堤高原の山に聞いてもいいですか？
so high
非常に高い
Then the plateau can be like this
そうすれば高原はこうなるかもしれない
such a large area
こんなに広いエリア
and then in the world there is no
そして世界には何もありません
One is that the area of ​​a plateau can be so large
1つは、高原の面積が非常に大きくなる可能性があるということです
a mountain
一個高山
Mountains that grow every year
毎年大きくなる山
mountains can be taller than them
山はそれよりも高いこともある
What are his conditions?
彼の条件は何ですか？
there are several answers
いくつかの答えがあります
English
英文
because there is no standard answer
標準的な答えがないから
What are the conditions?
条件は何ですか?
I have studied this Tibet for many years
私は長年チベットを研究してきました
when i spoke from the beginning
最初から話したら
The questions you ask are all questions that I want to solve or answer
あなたの質問はすべて私が解決したい、答えたい質問です
or a question that many people want to answer
または多くの人が答えたい質問
So every time I started doing it ten years ago
だから10年前にそれをやり始めるたびに
Every speech should say these things
すべてのスピーチでこれらのことを言う必要があります
But because I've been talking for so many years
でも何年も話してきたから
so i forget about him now
だから今は彼のことを忘れています
or don't want to talk about it
あるいはそれについて話したくない
Because no one has been able to answer so far
今のところ誰も答えられないから
It seems a bit arrogant to say that.
そう言うのは少し傲慢な気がします。
But there are many difficult answers in the middle
しかし、途中には難しい答えがたくさんあります
Like one of our opponents, a professor at UCL called Harrison
私たちの反対者の一人であるハリソンというUCLの教授のように、
He often said that Tibet is unique in his speeches
彼は演説の中でチベットは独特だとよく言った。
so do tibetan research
チベット研究もそうだ
There is no way to apply to any other shape in
他の形状に適用する方法はありません。
Any other shape gaining knowledge
知識を得るその他の形状
There is no way to apply to Tibet
チベットに申請する方法はありません
So this is the core part of your question
これがあなたの質問の核心部分です
This is UCL
これがUCLです
The so-called big name is called the National Academy of Sciences
いわゆるビッグネームは全米科学アカデミーと呼ばれます
How dare he speak so loudly
彼はどうしてそんなに大声で話すことができるのか
Why is the new assembly so high?
なぜ新しい議会はこれほど高いのでしょうか？
Simply put, India collides with Asia
簡単に言えば、インドはアジアと衝突する
indian asian crash
インド アジア人 クラッシュ
So India started colliding around 60 million years ago
つまり、インドは約6000万年前に衝突を始めたということになる
but after the collision
しかし衝突後
The speed still continues to be measured according to the current GPS global satellite positioning
速度は、現在の GPS 全地球衛星測位に従って引き続き測定されます。
It still continues to make relative motion to the north at the speed of 4 cm every year
現在も毎年4cmの速度で北へ相対運動を続けています。
didn't quite stop
なかなか止まらなかった
So the category that pushes north is obviously the main support
したがって、北に進む階級が主な支持者であることは明らかです
Why can support Tibet be folded up so high
なぜチベットへの支持がこれほどまでに高まるのか
then always
それからいつも
High spin does not collapse there
そこではハイスピンが崩れない
According to the model of mountain movement, it means that the mountain grows to a certain height
山の動きのモデルによれば、山が一定の高さまで成長することを意味します
When the balance of variety shows cannot be maintained
バラエティ番組のバランスが取れなくなったとき
it's going to collapse
それは崩壊するだろう
But Tibet is very strange
しかしチベットはとても奇妙だ
It has been maintained for 5 or 6 ten million years, but it will not collapse for 50 or 60 million years
5000～6000万年維持されているが、5000～6000万年は崩壊しない
There must be some special mechanism
何か特別な仕組みがあるに違いない
So there are many special mechanisms
特別な仕組みがたくさんあるので、
Including our article also thought about some
私たちの記事も含めていくつか考えました
let me explain
説明させてください
But this one has a lot of details
しかし、これには多くの詳細があります
So if you are really interested
それで本当に興味があるなら
That doesn't seem to be very respectful of your question.
それはあなたの質問をあまり尊重していないようです。
If you want to know more details
さらに詳しく知りたい場合は
maybe after that is over
たぶんそれが終わってから
I can specifically explain some details to you
いくつかの詳細を具体的に説明できます
okay
わかった
In this way, can I have to take a class before I can speak?
このように、話せるようになる前に授業を受けなければならないでしょうか?
Come to the Department of Geology, National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学地質学部に来てください
sorry professor
ごめんなさい教授
Can I ask you some historical gossip
歴史的なゴシップについて聞いてもいいですか
I know where the voice comes from
声がどこから来るのか知っています
later
後で
OK good
いいよ
you just mentioned that
あなたは今それを言いました
On the holy mountain there may be Noah Fang
聖なる山にはノア・ファングがいるかもしれない
not i mentioned
私が言及したのではありません
stories in the bible
聖書の中の物語
The holy mountain mentioned in Noah Fang State is that mountain
ノア・ファング州で語られる聖山はあの山です
Don't know means you are in the process of investigating
わからないということは調査中であることを意味します
is there some history
何か歴史はありますか
There are some foundational governments on earth that can prove
現場では、それを証明できる基礎的な政府がいくつかあります。
No
いいえ
is indirect
間接的です
then you can you just mentioned
それなら、今言ったようにできますか
I don’t know if you have heard some stories that are different from the Greek mythology we read in the local investigation
現地調査で読んだギリシャ神話とは異なるいくつかの話を聞いたことがあるかどうかはわかりません
You didn't either She didn't even have the Trojan horse and now the new Trojan horse looks ugly
トロイの木馬さえなくなっていなかったのに、新しいトロイの木馬は醜く見えます
It's better in the movie
映画のほうがいいよ
the problem is
問題は
Thank you teacher for your wonderful speech. The question I want to ask the teacher is in the history of the earth.
先生、素晴らしいスピーチをありがとうございました。先生に聞きたいのは、地球の歴史に関する質問です。
Has there ever been a plateau as large as Tibet?
チベットほど大きな高原がかつてあったでしょうか?
Same question as him, tried not to answer, and here you are again
彼と同じ質問、答えないようにしていた、そしてまたここに来た
But Mr. Luo Xinghua, a graduate of our fourth department, is a student and is now a teacher at the University of Hong Kong.
しかし、私たちの第4学部の卒業生である羅星華氏は学生であり、現在は香港大学の教師をしています。
The University of Hong Kong is called that question that is so difficult to answer
香港大学はその答えが難しい質問と呼ばれています
There are many speculations or guesses whether there is a similar situation with Tibet
チベットにも同様の状況があるかどうか、多くの憶測や推測がある
One of the conjectures is that the mainland scholars said that China's North China
推測の一つは、本土の学者らは中国の華北は、
North China Block 或North China Crayton
華北ブロックまたは華北クレイトン
During the Mesozoic Era, because of the collision of the North China road blocks
中生代、中国北部の道路封鎖の衝突により
May have been so tall by Taiwanese
台湾人にとってはこんなに背が高かったのかもしれない
There are many low thickenable speech like
のような厚みの低いスピーチがたくさんあります
Ela Kaiz That Formation
エラ・カイズ・ザット・フォーメーション
So they said that once in the Zhongzheng Dynasty
それで彼らはかつて中正の時代にこう言いました。
had the eastern part of china
中国の東にあった
There used to be a plateau as large as Tibet
かつてはチベットと同じくらいの高原があった
but only explanations or doctrines
ただし説明や教義だけ
or speculation
または推測
yes many people believe
はい、多くの人が信じています
There are also many people who do not believe
信じない人も多い
Then apply it to the past history of the earth
そしてそれを地球の過去の歴史に当てはめる
because the time is longer
時間が長くなるから
This is the problem of geological record keeping.
これは地質学的記録の保存の問題です。
so it's hard to really do a direct comparison
したがって、実際に直接比較することは困難です
So I still can't answer you
だからまだ答えられない
some problems
いくつかの問題
problem to i have a problem
問題があります
you come as a tour guide
ツアーガイドとしてのあなた
We use the guide this geologist's
私たちはこの地質学者のガイドを使用します
It shows that Huangshan in the Huangshan mainland is very famous
黄山本土の黄山が非常に有名であることを示しています
I haven't been there yet
まだ行ったことがない
Granite Huangshan
花崗岩の黄山
Like the mountain in Zhangjiajie
張家界の山のように
That geology is very famous
その地質はとても有名です
I thought you were there
あなたがそこにいると思った
Have you ever been to Zhangjiajie?
張家界に行ったことがありますか？
nor
または
then you go
それならあなたは行き​​ます
I've been there
私はそこに行ったことがあります
The three mountains are different
３つの山は違う
he might be able to speak better for me
彼は私のためにもっと上手に話せるかもしれない
The geology of Huangshan and the mountains of Zhangjiajie
黄山と張家界の山々の地質
it was the sea
それは海でした
then the table rises
するとテーブルが上がります
then bluestone
それからブルーストーン
Then the geology is different
それなら地質も違う
Huangshan is Huajiangyan
黄山は華江堰です
Hua Jiangyan’s words are actually similar to South China’s
華江燕氏の言葉は実は中国南部の言葉と似ている
The one in the southeast of China
中国南東部のもの
When Zhou Shen took
周申が取ったとき
very broad
非常に広い
Especially in the second season of Bai
特にバイのセカンドシーズンでは
Very extensive Huaganyan activities are related
非常に広範な Huaganyan の活動が関連しています
Nahua Dry Rock Activities
ナワ ドライ ロックのアクティビティ
At that time, the general explanation was that
当時の一般的な説明は次のとおりでした。
When in Zhongzheng belt
中正帯の場合
At that time there was the ancient Pacific Ocean
当時、古代の太平洋がありました
Four percent of the ocean in the ancient Pacific
古代太平洋の海の4パーセント
Submerged in the northwest direction
北西方向に水没
So in the southeast of what is now China
それで、現在の中国の南東部で
the southeastern edge of Asia
アジアの南東の端
Formed a time like the Antize Hills
アンティーズヒルズのような時代を形成した
something like that
そんな感じ
So the flower dry rock in Huangshan is
つまり、黄山の花枯岩は
A bunch of flower dry rock activities
お花いっぱいのドライロックアクティビティ
A product of the Huochen activity looks like this
Huochenアクティビティの成果物はこんな感じ
Then he is Hualei Rock
それから彼は華麗岩です
So the position he invaded
それで彼が侵入した位置は
The flower bud rock in Huangshan should not be so deep at the beginning
黄山の花芽岩は最初はそれほど深くないはずです
It should be at a depth of five to ten kilometers
深さは5〜10キロメートルのはずです
So the five to ten kilometers on the surface
つまり、地表の5〜10キロメートル
After the crust peeled off
クラストが剥がれた後
Then he lays on top of that
それから彼はその上に横たわります
As for why Huangshan looks so good-looking
黄山がなぜあんなにイケメンに見えるのかというと、
This is beyond the scope of address science
これはアドレス科学の範囲を超えています
I can't help you pour oil
油を注ぐのを手伝うことはできません
That Zhangjialu is a dungeon
張家路はダンジョンだということ
I found that I eat food so far away
とても遠くで食べ物を食べていることに気づきました
but because i've been
でも私はそうだったので
The Danxia Mountain in Guangdong
広東省の丹霞山
if you have been
行ったことがあるなら
Those who haven't been can go and see
行ったことない人も見に行ってみよう
That too
それも
not exactly similar
全く似ていない
But it’s basically the same dungeon with minor differences
基本的には同じダンジョンですが、細かい違いがあります
It was from the time of the Mesozoic Era
中生代の頃からあった
The mainland in South China is a stable one
中国南部の本土は安定している
platform is called platform
プラットフォームはプラットフォームと呼ばれます
There are a lot of
がたくさんあります
The itinerary with a lot of limestone in Lampton
ランプトンの石灰岩が多い旅程
and then at the same time some
そして同時にいくつかの
The dungeon itinerary in Silent Rock
サイレントロックのダンジョンの旅程
but then
しかしその後
The so-called orogeny from Baierji to the Cenozoic Era
バイエルジから新生代までのいわゆる造山運動
It took a lot of talking about that orogeny
その造山運動についてはかなりの議論が必要でした
Because many experts have different models
多くの専門家が異なるモデルを持っているため
So I better not be exposed in it
だから露出しないほうがいいよ
Then it starts from the Shenxi environment of the diving sea
それからダイビング海の神西環境から始まります
Then it became the present land heart
それが今の陸心となる
Then mainly Taiwan is born above sea level
それから主に台湾は海面上に生まれます
If the Taiwan grows above sea level, it will accept erosion
台湾が海面より高く成長すれば浸食を受け入れるだろう
As long as the principle is below sea level
原則が海面以下である限り
You are Think
あなたは考える
You can accept Luyuan to Shenxi environment there
そこに陸源から神西環境を受け入れることができます
But once above sea level
しかし海抜を超えると
you become more than erosion benchmarks equal to
あなたは侵食ベンチマーク以上のものになります
You become the source of erosion
あなたは浸食の源になる
Then start to accept the later erosion
そしてその後の浸食を受け入れ始める
Probably it should be like this
たぶんこうなるはず
Okay, thank you
大丈夫ありがとう
is there any problem
何か問題ある
teacher, i want to ask
先生、聞きたいのですが
You just said you could know a certain rock
あなたは今、特定のロックについて知ることができると言いました
Travel a few kilometers below the surface
地表から数キロメートル下を移動する
then i want to know which one
じゃあどっちなのか知りたい
How does he know how many kilometers he travels?
彼は何キロ移動しますか?どうやって知っていますか?
Thanks
ありがとう
A few kilometers of travel, for example, in the case of Huaganye
たとえば、Huaganye の場合、数キロメートルの移動
Kanno has some special minerals
菅野には特別な鉱物がある
Special minerals are most common
特殊なミネラルが最も一般的です
do we have walls of kangaroo here
ここにカンガルーの壁はありますか
Or have you seen that kangaroo has three main minerals
あるいは、カンガルーには 3 つの主要なミネラルがあるのを見たことがありますか?
his name is mineralogy
彼の名前は鉱物学です
with quartz
石英付き
is a transparent mineral
透明な鉱物です
So the one in Huakanye
それで、ワカニエのものは
translucent or transparent mineral
半透明または透明な鉱物
The most transparent mineral is quartz
最も透明な鉱物は石英です
In addition to quartz, there is a white mineral called feldspar
石英の他に長石という白い鉱物もあります。
Feldspar is opaque but mainly white so that sometimes it will be a little hairy
長石は不透明ですが、主に白いため、少し毛が生えていることがあります。
the red mineral
赤い鉱物
And then there's another mineral called Feather Mother
そして、フェザーマザーと呼ばれる別の鉱物があります
The feather mother is black and easy to see, often in pieces
母羽は黒くて目立ちやすく、しばしばばらばらになっている
will see these minerals
これらの鉱物が見られます
Except that this mineral is sometimes compared
この鉱物は時々比較されることを除いて
We call it the more neutral Huakanye
私たちはそれをより中立的なフアカニエと呼んでいます
In fact, you will see in diorite or diorite diorite
実際には、閃緑岩または閃緑岩で見られます。
A black mineral called amphibole
角閃石と呼ばれる黒い鉱物
foot amphibole sure you have a chance to see if you go
足の角閃石、行ったら必ず見るチャンスがあるよ
Datun Mountain, Yangming Mountain, National Park
大屯山、陽明山、国立公園
Look at those words of Anshan eye
鞍山のその言葉を見てください
you can easily see stepping stones
飛び石が簡単に見えます
how do we know its intrusive formation
その侵入的な形成をどのようにして知ることができますか
What about the cooling temperature and pressure of the magma?
マグマの冷却温度と圧力はどうなるでしょうか?
to analyze the minerals in it
その中のミネラルを分析する
especially stepping stones or mica
特に飛び石や雲母
feldspar composition
長石の組成
Feldspar these minerals
長石、これらの鉱物
There is a mass of elements
要素の塊があります
It is related to temperature and pressure
温度と圧力が関係しています
So according to this comparison
したがって、この比較によれば、
We can build something called a geothermometer
地温計と呼ばれるものを構築できます
or geometer stuff
または幾何学的なもの
So look at some special minerals in it
特別なミネラルが含まれていることに注目してください
What is the mass of chemical composition
化学組成の質量は何ですか
We can calculate its equilibrium temperature and equilibrium pressure
平衡温度と平衡圧力を計算できます。
like this
このような
pressure from balance
バランスからの圧力
How deep can we push it
どこまで深く押し込めるか
So we can put this rock mass
それで、この岩の塊を置くことができます
or the temperature and pressure at which this rock crystallizes or cools
または、この岩石が結晶化するか冷却される温度と圧力
can be calculated
計算できる
no difference from now on
これからも変わらない
No difference, because it's too much trouble to hold hands
違いはないよ、手を繋ぐのが面倒だから
so that detail
だからその詳細
Thanks
ありがとう
Well, if there's no problem, we have one more
さて、問題なければ、もう一つあります
Teacher, listened to so much heavy stuff tonight
先生、今夜は重い話をたくさん聞きました
I want to ask a simple question
素朴な質問をしたいのですが
I'm curious, since when did the teacher become interested in stones?
気になるのですが、先生はいつ頃から石に興味を持たれたのでしょうか？
something so hard and so hard
何かとても難しくてとても難しい
how can it be so funny
どうしてそんなに面白いんだろう
Because I think many children will come to participate today
今日はたくさんの子供たちが参加すると思うので
they are
彼らです
The standard answer is that I became interested after I entered the Department of Geology at National Taiwan University
標準的な答えは、国立台湾大学の地質学部に入学してから興味を持ったというものです。
just started
はじまったばかり
Actually no, I wasn’t very interested in it when I entered the Department of Geology at National Taiwan University.
いえ、実は国立台湾大学地質学科に入学したときはあまり興味がありませんでした。
My senior is here, he might fine me at this time
私の先輩がここにいるので、今度は私に罰金を科すかもしれません
I didn't know what to do until after I graduated from college
大学卒業するまで何をすればいいのか分からなかった
At that time I wanted to be a soldier
当時は軍人になりたかった
just give society to do something else
社会に何か別のことをやらせるだけだ
but i met a good teacher
でも良い先生に出会えた
My teacher is Chen Zhenhong
私の先生は陳振紅です
Maybe you've heard his name
彼の名前を聞いたことがあるかもしれません
He was the former vice chairman of Congress
彼は元議会副議長でした
If you've ever watched the congressional news
議会ニュースを見たことがあるなら
Called Hi by Chen Zhenhong
チェン・ジェンホンからこんにちはと呼ばれました
so let me go to his grad school
だから彼の大学院に行かせてください
And from then on that one went on this road of no return
そしてそれ以来、人は引き返せない道を進んだ
Only discovered after the point of no return
帰還不能点の後でのみ発見される
interested in this
これに興味がある
Maybe it's not necessarily what I wanted to do when I was a child
必ずしも子供の頃にやりたかったことではないかもしれない
specially bred
特別に育てられた
when you infoed in it
あなたがそれを情報したとき
and found inside
そして中で見つけた
there are some fun things
楽しいことがいくつかあります
At least you can go sightseeing, right?
観光くらいはできるんじゃないでしょうか？
But some people don't like traveling
でも旅行が嫌いな人もいる
On the contrary, I feel that it is very hard to go there.
逆にそこに行くのはとても大変だと思います。
like many kids nowadays
最近の多くの子供たちと同じように
No, no, a kid from the Department of Geology, National Taiwan University
いいえ、いいえ、国立台湾大学地質学科の子供です。
You have to ask him to climb that mountain
あなたは彼にその山に登るよう頼まなければなりません
or go there to play
またはそこに遊びに行ってください
he will find it fun
彼はそれが楽しいと思うだろう
There are many homeboys and homegirls in the Geology Department of National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学の地質学部にはホームボーイやホームガールがたくさんいます
If you also like to travel in mountains and rivers
山や川を旅するのも好きなら
Must be ranked
ランク付けする必要があります
if running outside
外で走っている場合
In fact, geology or technical science
実際、地質学や技術科学
there should be many
たくさんあるはずです
The interests that can be cultivated are in it
培える興味はそこにある
That's why I became interested after I entered the Geology Department of National Taiwan University.
それで、国立台湾大学の地質学科に入学してから興味を持ちました。
actually right
実際に正しい
The so-called gas station on the ground is completely out of the field, which is very hard.
いわゆる地上のガソリンスタンドは完全にフィールド外なので大変です。
no air condition
エアコンなし
There may not be breakfast, there may not be anything
朝食がないかもしれない、何もないかもしれない
It's hard work being outside
外での仕事は大変です
Assuming a joke, I went to Sumen University to run wild at the beginning of a year
冗談のつもりで、年の初めにスメン大学に暴れに行ってきました
with one of my new postdocs
新しいポスドクの一人と
Then after renting for one night, he told me the next day
そして一晩借りた翌日、彼は私にこう言いました。
Why doesn't this hotel have a shower head in the bathroom
なぜこのホテルのバスルームにはシャワーヘッドがないのですか
OK, we finally thank Mr. Dong for his wonderful speech
OK、最後にドン氏の素晴らしいスピーチに感謝します。
let's be a lot of rocks
たくさんの石になろう
Thank you puffs thank you
ありがとうパフ、ありがとう
You
あなた